who came to play this perfect round of军 insert Cassie neck
キャシー ネックを挿入するこの完璧なラウンドをプレイするために来たのは誰ですか
replaces our
私たちの代わりになります
Colleagues of the Intermediate Court and our good neighbors
中級裁判所の同僚と私たちの良き隣人たち
good night everybody
おやすみ皆さん
we are very happy today
私たちは今日とても幸せです
We invite you to our courtyard
あなたを中庭にご招待します
Director of the Agricultural Biotechnology Center
アグリバイオテクノロジーセンター長
Dr. Citizen came to speak to us.
シチズン博士が私たちに話をしに来ました。
Then this Director Shi, he was a few years ago in 2008
そしてこの施監督は数年前の2008年に
We worked very hard to bring him back from Yan'an abroad
私たちは彼を延安から海外に連れ戻すために一生懸命働きました
When he was abroad, he was in
彼が海外にいたとき、彼はそこにいました
the elvo university
エルボ大学
Before this, he graduated from the Biology Department of our Tunghai University
これに先立って、彼は東海大学の生物学部を卒業しました。
Go abroad after graduation
卒業後は海外へ
There should be soldiers, right?
兵士がいるはずですよね？
Just to ask
問一下
Go abroad to Alvor University
アルヴォル大学へ留学
this
これ
Studying for a Ph.D.
博士号取得を目指して勉強中
Then went to Harvard to do research for a while
それからハーバード大学に行ってしばらく研究しました
Then he was invited back to be a professor by his alma mater
その後、彼は母校から教授として再び招かれました。
When it comes to this, there is also a director of the laboratory
こうなると研究室長もいる
very well done
非常によくやりました
we were
私たちはいた
Agricultural Biotechnology Research Center
アグリバイオテクノロジー研究センター
Also just being restructured
こちらもリストラされたばかり
After several years of preparation
数年の準備期間を経て
former preparatory office
旧準備室
can be regarded as the director
ディレクターとみなすことができる
Director Yang Qingsun also worked for a long time
ヤン・チンソン監督も長く働いた
Laid out the technology very well
テクノロジーを非常にうまくレイアウトしました
After the director comes back
監督が戻ってきたら
in Taiwan
台湾で
related to our agriculture
私たちの農業に関わるもの
Together
一緒
do it really well
本当にうまくやる
with the Council of Agriculture
農業委員会と
the farmer
農民
Course Basic Studies
コース基礎学習
are full of in-depth
奥深い内容が満載です
practice
練習
so today we
だから今日私たちは
very happy to talk about this topic
このトピックについて話せてとても嬉しいです
because of this issue
この問題のせいで
now more and more important
今ではますます重要になっています
we yesterday
私たちは昨日
in the yard now
院裡面現在
A recently established
最近設立された
issues of sustainable development
持続可能な開発の問題
sustainable development inside
内部の持続可能な発展
Of course, this includes a lot. What you may be thinking is that
もちろん、これには多くのことが含まれます。
This climate change is causing many problems now
この気候変動を考えると、現在多くの問題を引き起こしています
Agriculture has also been hit hard
農業も大打撃を受けている
Someone told me yesterday that if Taiwan did not have these natural disasters
昨日誰かが私にこう言いました、もし台湾に自然災害がなかったら
Like this typhoon, the vegetables and fruits produced by our agriculture, etc.
今回の台風のように、私たちの農業で生産された野菜や果物なども。
It's all too much process
プロセスが多すぎる
Well, our technology is actually very good.
そうですね、私たちの技術は実際には非常に優れています。
Recently, in fact, you have also seen these bananas for sale.
実は、あなたも最近このバナナを見たことがあるでしょう。
It made President Ma very nervous.
それは馬総統を非常に緊張させた。
so this
したがって、この
I said we are very, actually very happy in Taiwan
私たちは台湾で本当にとても幸せだと言いました
We do not lack these agriculture
私たちにはこれらの農業が欠けていません
But there are many countries that have food shortages and other problems
しかし、食糧不足やその他の問題を抱えている国はたくさんあります
So this future agriculture
つまり、この未来の農業は
Must rely on these more advanced
これらのより高度な機能に依存する必要があります
Technology can help us solve many problems
テクノロジーは多くの問題の解決に役立ちます
recurring problem or
繰り返し起こる問題や、
drought etc.
干ばつなど
Therefore, Director Shi's research
そこで、施所長の研究は、
is an expert in this field
この分野の専門家です
For the so-called adverse environment
いわゆる悪環境に対しては
This effect on plants
植物に対するこのような影響
Adversity, you may not be able to understand
逆境では理解できないかもしれない
what adversity is
逆境とは何ですか
because it is stress
それはストレスだから
In fact, a relatively simple
実際、比較的単純な
Liu Zhang and Vice President
劉張氏と副総統
When I was the principal of Chuo University
私が中央大学の校長だった頃
He suddenly likes the Middle East, Chinese and Western
彼は突然中東、中国、西洋が好きになりました
He kept asking about Zhongnan papaya
彼は中南パパイヤについて尋ね続けた
Why is there no flowering or fruiting
なぜ開花や結実がないのか
their driver told him
彼らの運転手は彼に言った
no problem you go get some nails
大丈夫、釘を取りに行ってください
Nail that trunk
トランクを釘付けにする
he asked
彼は尋ねた
It really blooms next year
来年は本当に咲きますよ
that is stress
それはストレスです
i think plants are in pain
植物は苦しんでいると思う
you nail it to him
あなたは彼にそれを釘付けにします
Then he has to react
それから彼は反応しなければなりません
what you guys are eating
皆さんは何を食べていますか
what black
なんて黒いの
Lian Wu what is it called?
Lian Wu それは何と呼ばれますか？
Lianwu of black pearl
黒真珠のリアンウー
It was also discovered by none of the farmers
これも農家の誰にも発見されなかった
A Phenomenon
現象
Lian Wu, which came out the next year, is very sweet and spicy
翌年に出たリアンウーはとても甘くて辛いです
that is also a kind of stress
それも一種のストレスです
But that's not easy to do
でもそれは簡単なことではありません
Later, in those lands, they used seawater to crown
その後、それらの土地では海水を冠に使用しました。
Those lands can't be used later
それらの土地は後で使用することはできません
So there should be other ways to do these stress
したがって、これらのストレスを軽減する他の方法があるはずです
that's us mayor
それが私たち市長です
Maybe I'll talk later, I don't know
たぶん後で話すことになるでしょう、わかりません
Another area that he is very concerned about now is
彼が現在非常に懸念しているもう一つの分野は、
Orchid, our grandma orchid in Taiwan
蘭、台湾のおばあちゃんの蘭
He has done a very in-depth research now
彼は今非常に詳細な研究を行っています
he may explain later
彼は後で説明するかもしれない
so this future
だからこの未来は
Everyone depends on him for food and food.
誰もが食べ物と食べ物を彼に依存しています。
So let's applaud him quickly. Come on.
それでは、早速彼に拍手を送りましょう。
good
良い
Thank you Dean Wang Wu
ディーン・ワン・ウーさん、ありがとう
this introduction
この紹介文
I probably can't bear it
たぶん耐えられないんだろうな
But I probably won't talk about much of my own research today.
しかし、今日は私自身の研究についてはあまり話さないでしょう。
But we should have plenty of time to ask questions
しかし、質問する時間は十分にあるはずです
so you can stay till the end
だから最後まで居られるよ
Let's just ask me those questions
それらの質問を私に聞いてみましょう
Then I didn't define what is called historical biotechnology at the beginning.
それから、最初に歴史的バイオテクノロジーというものを定義しませんでした。
Then I hope that by the end
それから、最後までにそうなることを願っています
Let's come back to discuss my reasoning
戻って私の推論を議論しましょう
Why I choose the topic of my talk today as the prospect of biotechnology in history
私が今日の講演のテーマを歴史におけるバイオテクノロジーの展望として選んだ理由
In fact, the Science and Technology Advisory Group of our Executive Yuan was around 2000
実際、行政院の科学技術諮問グループは 2000 年頃に設立されました。
just defined biotechnology
ちょうど定義されたバイオテクノロジー
He said that biotechnology is the use of biological programs
彼は、バイオテクノロジーとは生物学的プログラムの利用であると述べた
Biological cells or their metabolites to manufacture products
製品を製造するための生体細胞またはその代謝物
Or scientific and technical personnel who improve the quality of human life
または人間の生活の質を向上させる科学技術関係者
If you use this definition is a relatively narrow definition
この定義を使用する場合は、比較的狭い定義になります。
Use this definition to define what is biotechnology
この定義を使用してバイオテクノロジーとは何かを定義します
if so
もしそうなら
Then let me start with the so-called green biotechnology
それでは、いわゆるグリーンバイオテクノロジーから始めましょう
just set it as
それを次のように設定してください
Primarily using cells related to plants
主に植物に関わる細胞を使用
or metabolize substances to make some products
または物質を代謝して何らかの製品を作る
over the past 20 years
過去20年間にわたって
That is to say, this so-called plant
つまり、このいわゆる植物は、
agricultural biotechnology or
農業バイオテクノロジーや
The most notable achievement of green biotechnology
グリーンバイオテクノロジーの最も注目すべき成果
many people will notice
多くの人が気づくでしょう
I'm a so-called genetically modified crop
私はいわゆる遺伝子組み換え作物です
So my speech today will be based on the period
したがって、今日の私のスピーチはその時代に基づいたものになります
Let me introduce you first
まずはご紹介させていただきます
GM crops
基改作物
but please
でもお願いです
If you have environmental protection against genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えに対する環境保護を行っている場合
don't be nervous
緊張しないで
I will also explain at the end
最後にも解説します
In fact, it means
実際、それが意味するのは、
not necessarily that is to say
必ずしもそうとは限りません
we do biotechnology
私たちはバイオテクノロジーを行っています
Must rely on genetically modified crops
遺伝子組み換え作物に頼らなければならない
So let's use fast
それでは早速使ってみましょう
we'll talk about it until the end
最後まで話しましょう
problems in this area
この分野の問題
that so
まあまあ
Because the application of biotechnology is the most important thing I'm talking about
私が話しているのはバイオテクノロジーの応用が最も重要なことだからです
Most notable achievement at the beginning
初期の最も注目すべき成果
genetically engineered crops
遺伝子組み換え作物
This technology actually has a very not great picture
このテクノロジーは実際にはあまり良くないイメージを持っています
But the very important picture is the so-called gene transfer technology
しかし、非常に重要な問題は、いわゆる遺伝子導入技術です。
This technology is not only available to those who make plants
この技術は植物を作る人だけが利用できるものではありません
People who work as animals or living things have
動物や生き物として働く人々は、
current technology words
現在のテクノロジーの言葉
Because there are some viewers who are not living beings and are trapped
閉じ込められた生き物ではない視聴者もいるから
so let me introduce a little bit
それで少し紹介させてください
all living things on earth
地球上のすべての生き物
Our genetic material is all on the so-called blue physiognomy
私たちの遺伝物質はすべて、いわゆる青い人相学に基づいています
The blue body is the DNA of the so-called double bone
青い体はいわゆる二重骨のDNAです
There may be thousands of genes on a single blue body
単一の青い体には数千の遺伝子がある可能性があります
We count each gene as a unit
各遺伝子を単位として数えます
The word of the gene will go through the so-called detour
遺伝子の言葉はいわゆる回り道を通る
so-called RNA
いわゆるRNA
To RMA it will...
RMAするには...
this is transfer, this is transfer
これは転送です、これは転送です
turn into protein
タンパク質に変わる
Most of the biological functions or structures
ほとんどの生物学的機能または構造
that protein is the most important
タンパク質が最も重要であるということ
So you're going to modify a creature
それで、あなたは生き物を改造するつもりです
What you have to change is to make it
あなたが変えなければならないのは、それを実現することです
that is to say it is protein
つまりプロテインです
production of a specific protein
特定のタンパク質の生産
or more or less
または多かれ少なかれ
or it doesn't make the protein in the first place
あるいは、そもそもタンパク質を作らない
you let it make this protein
このタンパク質を作らせます
That's the easiest way to do it
それが一番簡単な方法です
you can achieve this
あなたはこれを達成できます
The easiest way is usually to
最も簡単な方法は通常、
you changed the gene
あなたは遺伝子を変えました
or if you don't want it to have this protein
または、このタンパク質を含ませたくない場合は、
You give this gene to...
あなたはこの遺伝子を...
give it to...we call NACAO off
それを与えてください...NACAOを中止します
i will remove it
私はそれを削除します
Then if you want it to express a new gene
新しい遺伝子を発現させたい場合
a new protein
新しいタンパク質
then you may use various methods
その後、さまざまな方法を使用できます
Insert this gene into this blue above
この遺伝子を上の青色に挿入します
so that it can express this kind of a foreign gene
この種の外来遺伝子を発現できるようにするため
Want
欲しい
This technology is what we call genetic modification
この技術は私たちが遺伝子組み換えと呼ぶものです
By definition, it is a bent gene
定義上、それは曲がった遺伝子です
into cells or individuals
細胞や個体に
The definition is simple
定義は簡単です
help easier
もっと簡単に手伝ってください
In total, it can be classified into these four types
合計するとこの4種類に分類されるようになりました。
The latter three can probably be used in animals, plants or microorganisms
後の 3 つはおそらく動物、植物、微生物に使用できます。
This gene gun is actually a gun
この遺伝子銃は実際には銃です
You're calling the gold one Lobarico
あなたは金のことをロバリコと呼んでいます
tiny gold particles
小さな金の粒子
wrap that DNA on it
そのDNAを包み込む
And then you literally take a gun and shoot it inside the cell
そして文字通り銃を手に取り独房の中で撃ちます
That is you can put this DNA
つまり、この DNA を入れることができます
cell passed to another cell
セルが別のセルに渡されました
These technologies are actually special instruments that you need.
これらのテクノロジーは、実際には必要な特別な機器です。
and they are quite expensive
そしてそれらはかなり高価です
So if you are an animal, you need to transfer the value of the animal
したがって、あなたが動物である場合は、その動物の価値を譲渡する必要があります
that technique is difficult
その技術は難しいです
that would be expensive for us
それは私たちにとって高価になるでしょう
Then in the plant it has a special method
それから工場では特別な方法があります
we are called
私たちは呼ばれています
Replanting method in the agricultural management circle
農業経営界における改植方法
Well, this is actually because we are doing plant molecular biology.
そうですね、実はこれは私たちが植物分子生物学をやっているからです。
The technology written from nature
自然から生み出されたテクノロジー
Then the replanting method of the agricultural management circle
それでは農業経営サークルの改植方法
The most important thing is in the natural world, I think if you see
最も重要なことは自然界にあると思います。
you have that tree by the road
あなたは道路のそばにあの木があります
Or if grass is not healthy
または芝生が健康でない場合
Things that often have a long flow will go off
流れが長いことが多いものは消えてしまいます
Well, this is actually the seed flow of plants.
そうですね、これは実際には植物の種子の流れです。
it's the plants
それは植物です
look at this
これを見てください
This is a very typical
これは非常に典型的なものです
For this cancer, it is usually the same as our cancer cells
このがんの場合、通常は私たちのがん細胞と同じです
It keeps growing where it shouldn't grow
成長してはいけない場所で成長し続ける
So maybe you are sometimes
だから、もしかしたらあなたも時々そうかもしれない
You grow more near the place
あなたはその場所の近くでさらに成長します
or are you there
それともあなたはそこにいるのですか
this is long is a kind of that
これは長いです、それはその一種です
It's just a meristem without specialization
専門性のないただの分裂組織だ
That's why it's happening in nature all day long
だからこそ自然界では一日中起こっているのです
The reason why there is such a flow
なぜそのような流れがあるのか​​というと、
that's because
それは
Agrobacterium has this ability
アグロバクテリウムにはこんな能力がある
it's bacteria
それは細菌です
a fungus in the soil
土壌の中の菌
Agrobacterium
アグロバクテリウム
English called Agrobacteria
英文叫 Agrobacterium
It carries itself with its own blue body
青い体で自らを運ぶ
It also has a function we call
私たちが呼び出す関数もあります
Tumor inducing possum
腫瘍誘発性ポッサム
It is equal to the carrier that you can self-cancer
自己がんになる可能性がある保因者に等しい
This carrier has a piece of DNA on it
このキャリアには DNA の一部が搭載されています
If you plant
植えたら
if there is injury
怪我がある場合
It will infect the plant with this bacteria
この細菌が植物に感染します
Then put this piece of DNA
それからこの DNA を入れてください
sent to the cell goose of the plant
工場の細胞ガチョウに送られる
then become plant cells
そして植物細胞になる
part of plant blue body
植物の青い体の部分
That one has a set of genes
あの人は遺伝子を持っている
its set of genes
その遺伝子セット
Is it the same as our human cancer cells?
それは人間のがん細胞と同じでしょうか？
It causes cancer cells to continue to divide
がん細胞の分裂を継続させます
Cancer cells then make some
がん細胞はその後、いくつかの物質を生成します。
Compound, what about this Seo Joon
コンパウンド、このソジュンはどうですか？
will use these compounds as its nutrients
これらの化合物を栄養素として使用します
So it's a natural phenomenon
だからそれは自然現象だよ
That is to say almost 30 years ago
つまり30年近く前になります
That is to say, some molecular biologists who work on plants
つまり、植物を研究する一部の分子生物学者は、
they figured out a way
彼らはある方法を考え出した
Take this set of DNA from the so-called Agrobacterium
いわゆるアグロバクテリウムからこの DNA セットを取り出します
replace it with harmless DNA
無害な DNA に置き換えます
That is to say if you have any DNA
つまり、DNAがあれば
you're going to put it in the plant
あなたはそれを工場に入れるつもりです
you just replace this paragraph
この段落を置き換えるだけです
If so
もしそうなら
then you can
そうすればできます
That is to say, you are the first to select a target gene
つまり、あなたが最初に標的遺伝子を選択するのです。
Then you put it in the Agrobacterium
それをアグロバクテリウムに入れます
And then you put it into the plant cells by the Agrobacterium
そして、それをアグロバクテリウムによって植物細胞に入れます。
Then you put the plant cells into the cultured genes
次に、培養した遺伝子を植物細胞に挿入します。
Then in words like this
そうすると、こんな言葉で
It's easy for you to have so-called genetically modified plants
いわゆる遺伝子組み換え植物を手に入れるのは簡単です
The reason why this genetically modified plant is so simple is
この遺伝子組み換え植物がなぜこんなにも単純なのかというと、
In addition to this agricultural sense coupon can send DNA to the cells of plants
この農業センスクーポンに加えて、DNAを植物の細胞に送ることができます
Most plants also have a very important characteristic
ほとんどの植物にも非常に重要な特徴があります
so-called tissue culture
いわゆる組織培養
For the plant, you have given it the proper grower
植物に関しては、あなたは適切な栽培者を与えました
You can put its cells in an incubator
細胞をインキュベーターに入れることができます
that is to say split
つまり分割する
Then after splitting, you change to a certain type of cultivator
分割後、特定のタイプの耕運機に変更します。
it will stick out its roots again
また根を張るだろう
Then you are changing to a certain type of incubator
次に、特定のタイプの保育器に変更します。
it will
そうなる
Grow this above ground leaf
この葉を地上に育てます
So these two properties
したがって、これら 2 つのプロパティ
Farm sense coupons can deliver DNA to plant cells
ファームセンスクーポンはDNAを植物細胞に届けることができます
Then
それから
Plants themselves have the so-called ability to regenerate
植物自体にはいわゆる再生能力があります
so
それで
stand up
立ち上がる
We do so-called plant molecular biologists you want to make a genetically modified crop
私たちはいわゆる植物分子生物学者で、遺伝子組み換え作物を作りたいと思っています。
In terms of animals, you do it one by one and we can do it at a time.
動物に関して言えば、あなたは一頭ずつそれを行いますが、私たちは一度にそれを行うことができます。
Just say it like this
こうやって言ってみろよ
So you are the genetic antison of your plant
つまり、あなたはあなたの植物の遺伝的アンチソンです
It's rich and cheap
豊富だし安いし
And it works and it's just not expensive
そしてそれは機能し、高価ではありません
So almost twenty years ago
それで、ほぼ20年前に
After this technology was invented
この技術が発明されてから
Scientists at that time thought
当時の科学者たちは考えました
This can be said to bring
これがもたらすものと言えるのは、
help with some agricultural issues
いくつかの農業問題を支援する
So at that time I thought those molecular biologists
それで当時私は分子生物学者はこう思ったのです
When I started doing it, I actually thought it was just saying
やり始めたときは、ただ言ってるだけだと思ってた
Because this is a relatively accurate plant species
これはより正確な植物種であるため、
Because every time you change your genes
遺伝子が変わるたびに
one gene at a time and puts it in another plant
一度に1つの遺伝子を別の植物に導入します
In fact, our ancestors did domain species
実際、私たちの祖先はドメイン種を作成しました
It has been done for thousands of years, tens of thousands of years
それは何千年、何万年もの間行われてきた
The techniques they use are actually very similar
彼らが使用するテクニックは実際には非常に似ています
It's just that they're replacing a segment, a whole segment of chromosomes.
それは染色体のセグメント、つまりセグメント全体を置き換えているだけです。
They have no way to accurately time
彼らには正確に時間を知る方法がない
I just need to change a segment, a gene
セグメント、遺伝子を変えるだけでいいのです
They exchange entire chromosomes
彼らは染色体全体を交換します
So we're genetically engineered and we can
つまり、私たちは遺伝子操作されており、
So we don't have to put the diagnostic chromosomes all at once
したがって、診断用の染色体をすべて一度に配置する必要はありません
In fact, most breeding in nature is unsuccessful.
実際、自然界におけるほとんどの繁殖は失敗に終わります。
Because you change so many chromosomes, the creatures you create can't compete
非常に多くの染色体を変更するため、作成した生物は太刀打ちできません
Just can't match the original Parental Strength
本来の親の力には敵わない
is its original copy or parent that competes
競合する元のコピーまたは親です
So now 20 years have this technology
このテクノロジーが確立されてから 20 年が経ちました
not only for researchers to do
研究者だけがやるべきことではない
Some so-called Multic Companies are also starting to do this
いわゆるMultic企業の一部もこれを始めています
In fact, there are several quite successful examples
実際、かなり成功した例がいくつかあります
The first is crops that are resistant to pests
1つ目は害虫に強い作物です。
Pest-resistant crops are actually learning from nature
害虫に強い作物は実は自然から学んでいる
There is a kind of building coupon in nature
自然界には一種の建物クーポンがあります
It secretes a toxin that kills
人を殺す毒素を分泌する
most insects
ほとんどの昆虫
In fact, GMOs existed before
実はGMOは以前から存在していた
farmers are already using
農家はすでに使用しています
that's them
それが彼らです
macrotrophs
大量養育菌
Then put Su Lixing's toxin
それからSu Lixingの毒素を入れてください
separate it
分けて
Then sprinkle it into the sky
それから空に撒いてください
this way to kill insects
この方法で虫を殺します
But this insecticide is very expensive
しかしこの殺虫剤はとても高価です
later you are
後であなたは
The range of killing is sometimes uncontrollable
殺害範囲は時には制御不能になる
Especially in European and American farms
特にヨーロッパやアメリカの農場では
he sprinkled words with ash
彼は言葉に灰をふりかけた
often spilled on
よくこぼれる
That is to say, the granddaughter who is near
つまり、近くにいる孫娘は、
the next one is
次は
he didn't kill
彼は殺しませんでした
that will kill
それは殺すだろう
may kill pests
害虫を殺すかもしれない
So this is like cotton now
これはもう綿のようなものです
and Hawaiian sugar cane
そしてハワイアンサトウキビ
Many of them have Su Lixing's genes
彼らの多くはSu Lixingの遺伝子を持っています
in him
彼の中で
In this way, it means
このようにすると、つまり、
He is more resistant to insects
他比較抗蟲
but
しかし
because you can't
できないから
if you just say
ただ言うなら
You put the whole area you want to plant
植えたいエリア全体を配置します
All insect resistant
あらゆる虫に強い
then soon
それからすぐに
From immediately it will evolve its anti-comfort properties
すぐにその反快適性が進化するでしょう
So they're doing GM lotus now or it's dry
だから彼らは今GMロータスをやってるか、それは乾いている
They say you have a special proportion
彼らはあなたが特別な比率を持っていると言います
For example, one tenth of you is the dryness of rock fairy
たとえば君の10分の1はロックフェアリーのドライさ
Ninety percent of this genetic modification
この遺伝子組み換えの90パーセントは
Then when you harvest like this
そうするとこうやって収穫すると
Once you come, you bug won't say that it has evolved drug resistance.
一度ここに来てしまえば、虫は薬剤耐性が進化したとは言わなくなるでしょう。
So this means that if you add this genetically modified crop to other methods of picking
つまり、この遺伝子組み換え作物を他の収穫方法に追加すると、
You can probably be like one person, a forest is the control
あなたはおそらく一人の人間のようになれるでしょう、森がコントロールです
That is to say, you don't say that caused this, that is,
つまり、それが原因だとは言っていない、つまり、
This evolution is very fast
この進化は非常に速いです
that will bring disaster to you again
それはまたあなたに災いをもたらすでしょう
So the combination of the two is actually quite effective.
したがって、この 2 つの組み合わせは実際には非常に効果的です。
So the dryness of Hawaii has probably been said for at least ten years
ハワイの乾燥はおそらく少なくとも10年前から言われてきたことになる
So far no major problems
今のところ大きな問題はありません
That's because it's traditional farming in other ways
それは別の意味で伝統的な農業だからです
Combined with biotech it becomes very ineffective
バイオテクノロジーと組み合わせると非常に効果がなくなる
Now China is growing a lot of cotton in the same way
現在、中国は同じ方法で綿花を大量に栽培しています
The other one is anti-sand sweeping chicken
もう1つは砂掃き防止チキンです
In fact, traditional agriculture
実は伝統的な農業は、
Especially in the United States, it is not called a collective farm
特にアメリカでは集団農場とは呼ばれません
If it's a big farm
大きな農場なら
Are they all small farmers in Asia?
彼らはすべてアジアの小規模農家ですか？
So their kitchen storage skills are handy.
そのため、キッチンの収納スキルは便利です。
Sprinkle it all in one piece
全てをひとまとめにふりかける
so usually very serious damage to the environment
通常、環境に非常に深刻なダメージを与える
So almost 20 years ago this Monsanto
それで、ほぼ20年前、モンサント社は
They did it with corn and soybeans
彼らはトウモロコシと大豆でそれをやった
Because they have a set of very good cooking skills
彼らは非常に優れた料理のスキルを持っているため、
That is BioDegradable
それは生分解性です
That is to say, it is not very residual
つまり残留性はあまり高くない
But the problem is it doesn't just kill weeds
しかし問題は、ただ雑草を枯らすだけではないということです
It also kills corn and soybeans
トウモロコシや大豆も枯らす
So-called herbicide-resistant chickens found
いわゆる除草剤耐性鶏が発見される
put it in the corn or put it in the big meat
トウモロコシの中に入れたり、大きな肉の中に入れたり
So when it sells weed killer
それで、除草剤を販売するときは、
sold with corn seeds
トウモロコシの種と一緒に売られている
Until now, it is the so-called run up ready corn
今まではいわゆる助走コーンです
This is it
これだよ
Then if you check the Council of Agriculture
そこで農業委員会を調べてみると、
Most of the corn we import is this
私たちが輸入しているトウモロコシのほとんどはこれです
So we have been eating for at least ten years
つまり、少なくとも10年間は​​食べ続けています
But this is actually if you evaluate it carefully
しかし、これは実際に注意深く評価してみると、
that's what it's really supposed to say
それが本当に言うべきことだ
still achieve its original purpose
まだ本来の目的を達成している
It's the one that makes COAG use less toxic
これは COAG の使用の毒性を軽減するものです
There are also cheaper weed killers
安価な除草剤もあります
But in fact, Meng Sanduo earns the most money
しかし実際には、孟三多が最も多くのお金を稼いでいる
Because it doesn't just sell weed killers
ただ除草剤を売っているだけではないので
it sells seeds too
種も売ってます
The other one is disease resistance
もう一つは耐病性です
Then I think this is the same as the anti-pest mentioned above.
それから、これは先ほどの防虫剤と同じだと思います。
should be the same principle
同じ原則であるはずです
that's it
それでおしまい
It can be naturally disease-resistant
自然に病気に強い可能性がある
or virus to drastically reduce pesticide use
またはウイルスで農薬の使用を大幅に削減
This is a relatively unsuccessful example
これは比較的失敗した例です
Because of the action of the plant's follower bacteria or fungi
植物の従属細菌や菌類の働きによるもの
very so-called specificity
非常にいわゆる特異性
Usually it's what we call Gene Fire Gene Hituo
通常、それは私たちがGene Fire Gene Hituoと呼ぶものです
That is, your plants of a certain strain can only resist a certain kind
つまり、特定の系統の植物は特定の種類の植物にしか耐性がありません。
That is to say, inside the same kind of bacteria
つまり、同じ種類の細菌の中に
it's all kinds of bad
それはあらゆる種類の悪いことです
I can't speak Chinese
私は中国語を話せません
just can't write
ただ書けないだけ
It's just different species from different places
各地から採れた小型種です
Generally speaking, special strains are required
一般的に言えば、特別な菌株が必要です
to resist this particular physiological race
この特定の生理学的人種に抵抗するために
So you have to develop a really resistant
だからあなたは本当に耐性を開発する必要があります
Not so easy for all races
すべての人種にとってそれほど簡単ではない
So this is a relatively unsuccessful example
これは比較的失敗した例です
The main reason is that our basic science is not good enough
主な理由は、私たちの基礎科学が十分ではないことです
Because we don't yet fully understand
まだ完全には理解できていないので、
that is
あれは
Why do you have to plant a gene
なぜ遺伝子を植える必要があるのか
And then this cellulite has a gene
そして、このセルライトには遺伝子があります
Then the two have to interact
それから二人は対話しなければなりません
To determine whether there will be resistance
抵抗があるかどうかを判断するには
Although we have done this
私たちはこれを行ってきましたが、
I think the world doesn't know how many scientists have been doing it for thirty or forty years
30年も40年も何人の科学者がこの研究を続けてきたのか、世界は知らないと思う
we know some but not all
私たちは一部は知っていますが、すべてを知っているわけではありません
So this is not a particularly successful example
したがって、これは特に成功した例ではありません
But I think if this can be done
でも、これができるならと思う
That's probably the ones I introduced earlier.
おそらく以前紹介したものだと思われます。
have the same material
同じ素材を持っています
The other is to say
もう一つは、こう言うことです
That this we can use the so-called biotechnology
これがいわゆるバイオテクノロジーを利用できるということ
to transform this important crop
この重要な作物を変えるために
The so-called high nutritional value crops
いわゆる栄養価の高い作物
And this one was almost twenty-five years ago
そして、これはほぼ25年前のことです
That is, a scientist in Switzerland
つまり、スイスの科学者です
He just did a set of experiments
彼はちょうど一連の実験を行ったところです
He can learn from that flower by taking the rice
お米を取ることで彼はその花から学ぶことができる
let him have a lot
彼にたくさん持たせてください
high vitamin production
ビタミンの生産量が多い
Vitamin A
ビタミンA
Then this is actually
それから、これは実は
He put this seed is unconditional
彼はこの種を無条件に置いた
It was unconditionally given to Huiser's country
それは無条件でホイザーの国に与えられた
That's actually very important
それは実はとても重要なことなのです
because in our asian country
なぜなら私たちのアジアの国では
especially in Taiwan
特に台湾では
We think our vegetables are very rich
私たちの野菜はとても豊富だと思います
So we don't think vitamin B
したがって、ビタミンBは考えられません
What's so great about vitamin A
ビタミンAの何がすごいのか
but in huiser country
しかし、ホイザー国では
because most of its children
なぜなら、その子供たちのほとんどが
source of nutrition
栄養源
Mainly rely on staple food
主に主食に頼る
so it's that
だからそれは
Many people just have that vitamin A
多くの人はビタミンAだけを持っています
The lack of that phenomenon
の欠如
that is, the disease
つまり病気です
If so, it will cause
そうなると、次のような原因になります
That is to say, the mans disease
つまり男性病です
that science
その科学
That is to say, it came out of the first generation
つまり初代から出てきた
it is attacked that is to say
つまり攻撃された
How many catties of rice do you need to eat a day?
1日に何斤の米を食べる必要がありますか?
you have the possibility
あなたには可能性があります
that is to say, what you call
つまり、あなたが求めるものを達成するために
enough vitamin A
十分なビタミンA
That this is what is called
これがいわゆる
That is to say link
つまりリンク
GMO people keep attacking it
GMOを攻撃し続ける人々
That's actually a wrong message
それは実際には間違ったメッセージです
Because after ten years of his work
なぜなら、彼の仕事の10年を経て、
the one he does now
彼が今やっていること
Let's say the amount of vitamin A he produces
彼が生成するビタミンAの量を考えてみましょう
already high enough
すでに十分に高い
That is to say, as long as you treat yourself as an ordinary host
つまり、普通のホストとして扱う限り、
you can make this
これを作ることができます
this do that gray state larvae
これは灰色の状態の幼虫をやります
can just say
ただ言える
get enough gray lights
十分な灰色の光を得る
That's actually a very
それは実際には非常に
And this scientist didn't apply for anything
そしてこの科学者は何も申請しなかった
patent he said
彼が言った特許
You need to know how to give gray light to the government
政府にグレーライトを与える方法を知る必要がある
But so far it doesn't work
しかし、今のところうまくいきません
Why
なぜ
because one of the most
なぜなら、最も
his earliest
他最早期
I used a very common carrier
ごく一般的なキャリアを使用しました
is a family
家族です
His patent is a
彼の特許は、
The very big Milote company
非常に大きなミロテ社
He has been refusing to unconditionally
彼はそれを無条件で拒否してきた
Give this to Louis and say
これをルイに渡して言ってください
Say this Yonago is going to be in Gray State
この米子がグレーステートになると言う
don't need
必要ありません
That is to say, match him with that or that or something
つまり、彼にあれやこれや何かを合わせてください
Patent Loyty's Ash
特許ロイティーズアッシュ
that to
それを
should go here
ここに行くべきです
These two years Burge Foundation should help
この 2 年間はバージ財団が支援すべきものです
Now this rice should be ready soon
さあ、このお米ももうすぐ出来上がるはずです
go to Huizhou
恵州に行く
But that's at least a decade behind
しかしそれは少なくとも10年は遅れている
That's because many scientists say the benefits are good
多くの科学者がメリットは良いと言っているからです
But in the end it's not really a matter of science
しかし結局のところ、それは実際には科学の問題ではありません
Instead, it becomes a Polish or economic problem
むしろ、ポーランドの問題や経済問題になる
That's a sad example
悲しい例ですね
Because when he did it more than 20 years ago
なぜなら、彼が20年以上前にそれをやったときは、
I mean it's a party
つまりパーティーだ
It's a pity that it's not available until now.
現在まで利用できないのが残念です。
Then do we have in Taiwan?
じゃあ台湾にもあるのか？
Yes, we in Taiwan actually have several genetic modification effects
はい、私たち台湾には実際にいくつかの遺伝子組み換え効果があります
It's just that we're saying there's no clear Polish
明確なポーランド語は存在しないと言っているだけです
So can you go up until now?
それで今まで上がれますか？
Without the effect of genetic modification made by us in Taiwan, it can be listed
台湾で当社が行った遺伝子組み換えの影響がなくても上場可能
Then that Dr. Zhenmincai from our Agricultural and Biological Center
それから、農業生物学センターのジェンミンツァイ博士です。
He said he did a few
彼はそれらのうちのいくつかをやったと言いました
Do a few. Tomatoes can resist salt and liver disease
トマトは塩分や肝臓病に強い
You may think that we don’t plant plants by the sea when we talk about salt resistance.
耐塩性というと、海沿いに植物を植えるわけではないと思われるかもしれません。
Why do anti-salt
なぜ反塩をするのか
Because we report that there are too many pesticides
農薬が多すぎると報告しているため
In fact, our soil has become slowly developed
実際、私たちの土壌はゆっくりと発展してきました
So you have to be persistent and good farmland will also become
だから粘り強くやっていかないと良い農地も出来上がってしまうのです。
The ion content in the soil will be too high
土壌中のイオン含有量が多すぎる
So salt resistance has always been a very hot topic
したがって、耐塩性は常に非常にホットな話題です
So Dr. Miantai successfully found several genes
そこでミアンタイ博士はいくつかの遺伝子の発見に成功した
You put it in a tomato and you can see it resists salt
トマトに入れると塩分に強いのがわかります
This is another group of anti-hepatic cases
これは抗肝疾患の別のグループです
The other is Dr. Ye Xidong, former vice president of Central University
もう一人は元中央大学副学長の葉希東博士です。
He is very famous for making papaya
彼はパパイヤ作りでとても有名です
Then his papaya's roulette virus
それから彼のパパイヤのルーレットウイルス
And that corporate virus
そしてその企業ウイルス
He has obtained double-resistant papaya
彼はすでに二重抵抗転移パパイヤを取得しています
The Council of Agriculture has approved him to conduct field experiments
農業評議会は彼が野外実験を行うことを承認した
But he also passed the food safety virus of our Department of Health
しかし、彼は保健省の食品安全ウイルスにも感染しました。
But the farmer is not going to put it in Taiwan
しかし、農家はそれを台湾に置くつもりはありません
Because Taiwan cannot be listed
台湾は上場できないから
This is available in India
これはインドで入手可能です
So this is probably for him to go to India
つまりこれはおそらく彼がインドに行くためだ
Then Wang Mu just talked about a papaya
それからワン・ムーはパパイヤについて話しました。
You hit it and it will bloom
打てば咲くよ
In fact, he has several types of papaya
実際、彼は数種類のパパイヤを持っています
that is to say he knows
つまり彼は知っている
Papaya bears the same plant as the magnetic bear
パパイヤは磁気クマと同じ植物を実らせます
So if you're only a bear
だから、もしあなたがただのクマだったら
It's useless for him to bloom
彼に咲いても無駄だ
But in stretch is in adversity
しかし、ストレッチには逆境がある
That is to say, you use iron nails or knock it a few times
つまり、鉄の釘を使用するか、数回ノックします。
you don't use nails
釘を使いませんか
Actually just knock a few times
実際には数回ノックするだけです
That is to say, cut it off when he gets hurt
つまり、怪我をしたら切るということです。
You will let it sometimes its bear will transform back to female
時々放っておくとクマがメスに戻ります
So this is or transforms into female bear and pig
これは雌のクマとブタに変身します
So at that time, it was not because it was afraid that it would become enlightened.
ですから、当時は悟りを開くのが怖かったわけではありません。
but because it needs to be gendered
しかし、性別を区別する必要があるため、
Then naturally there is this evolution, it has this so-called Beauty in the system
そして当然、この進化があり、システムにはいわゆる「美しさ」が備わっています。
It is to let you be in the reception because in fact, the most important purpose of all living things is to wear
実際、すべての生き物の最も重要な目的は、着用することであるため、あなたを受付に立たせることです。
Then if you only grow bears in one place
では、クマを一か所だけで育てた場合、
Then it will find a way to change
そうすれば変わる方法が見つかるだろう
So this Juris Park and that have some basis
つまり、このジュリスパークとあれには何らかの根拠があるのです
The papaya itself is actually you just need to give it environmental adversity
パパイヤ自体は、実際には、環境に逆境を与えるだけで十分です。
It's a little bit bearish and it's going to be late
ちょっと弱気だし手遅れになりそう
Then it can be solved like this
そうすると、このように解決できます
The other one is Dr. Chen Longwang from our Institute of Academia Sinica
もう一人は中央研究院の陳龍王博士です。
All he did was make broccoli prolong life
彼がやったのはブロッコリーを長生きさせただけだ
what he does is you turn this upside down
彼がやっているのは、あなたがこれをひっくり返すことです
Just put a gene in this broccoli
このブロッコリーに遺伝子を入れてください
you take it off
あなたはそれを脱ぎます
and after you cut it
そしてカットした後は
This is Wild Time
これはワイルドタイムです
You can see he's just talking about circularizing soon
彼がすぐに循環化することについて話しているのがわかります
this is his
これは彼のです
that is to say he did
つまり彼はやったということだ
just say something like this
このようなことを言ってください
after you have accumulated
積み上げた後は
the one he can have at the market
彼が市場で手に入れることができるもの
That is to say, the life span will be longer
つまり寿命が延びるということです
Then I want these slides
それから、これらのスライドが欲しいです
have their condition
彼らの状態がある
So you can also put it here
なので、ここに置くこともできます
the other one is
もう一つは
Dr Hong Dong-won from our Central Post Office
中央郵便局のホン・ドンウォン医師
Dr. Hong Dongyuan from Tian Jiaozhong
Tian Jiaozhong のホン・ドンユアン博士
Find the two proteins that affect job-related allergic reactions
仕事に関連したアレルギー反応に影響を与える 2 つのタンパク質を見つける
Then you put these two proteins together with Xun Xing
次に、これら 2 つのタンパク質を Xun Xing と組み合わせます。
he will cause
彼は引き起こすだろう
Anti-disease mechanism that promotes duty
義務を促進する抗疾病メカニズム
that this
これは
Huang Dengyong is my senior
黄登永は私の先輩です
he with that
彼はそれを持って
The scientist who made the golden rice mentioned above has the same attitude
前述のゴールデンライスを作った科学者も同じ態度だ
He thinks biotech can do good
彼はバイオテクノロジーが良いことをもたらすと考えている
So he has a patent
つまり彼は特許を持っている
But patents are not for sale
しかし、特許は売り物ではありません
he is going to help others
彼は他の人を助けるつもりです
So Mr. Feng is traveling around the world
それで馮さんは世界中を旅しています
Then he later discovered that in Africa, especially in Central Africa, the Yana generation
その後、アフリカ、特に中央アフリカではヤナ世代が
Bananas are their main source of telegrams
電報の主な供給源はバナナです
In recent years, they have had that banana and that tail-adjustment disease
近年、彼らはバナナと尾の調整の病気を患っています
Teacher Feng was very enthusiastic to apply.
フェン先生はとても熱心に応募してくれました。
Woolen
ウール
Then train the scientists of this pit ya
それからこの穴の科学者を訓練してください
teach them how to make GM bananas
GMバナナの作り方を教えてください
Later the BioGate Foundation paid
その後、BioGate Foundation が支払いを行いました
It is to let the government in Kengya start to have a system to do this
ケンギャ政府にこれを行うためのシステムを導入させようというものです
It means that we are the best in biology, so we can introduce this in it.
それは我々が生物学の分野で一番優れているということなので、生物学の中でこれを導入できるということです。
The results of this experiment by Mr. Huang Fangyong
黄方永氏による今回の実験結果
Then this Central Plains Institute was when the Dean of the Idea
そして、このセントラルプレーンズ研究所は、アイデア学部長の頃でした。
patent
特許
hand him over to the government of the world
彼を世界政府に引き渡す
so that they can experiment with this
彼らがこれを実験できるように
Well I guess this isn't really meant to help
まあ、これは本当に役立つものではないと思います
The issue of the laser in the countries of China and Wiener
中国とウィーン諸国におけるレーザーの問題
this is very important
これはとても重要です
Because intersecting is really what they host
なぜなら交差こそが彼らが主催するものだからです
if there is no medicine
薬がなかったら
that is to say you have so far
つまり、これまでのところ
And you can't find the insecticide that works
効く殺虫剤も見つからない
It's just that your chemicals aren't very effective.
ただ、化学薬品の効果があまり高くないのです。
So this is a
これは
It's actually a great contribution
実際、非常に大きな貢献です
That Mr. Huang just gave this for free
黄氏がこれを無料で提供したということ
So I told those few examples
そこで私はそれらのいくつかの例を話しました
That is to say, those of us
つまり、私たち人間は、
It is my predecessors and scientists of our generation
それは私の先人たちであり、私たちの世代の科学者です。
We do these things in fact we feel
私たちはこれらのことを実際に行っていると感じています
That is, if you're doing the right thing about so-called biotechnology
つまり、いわゆるバイオテクノロジーに関して正しいことをしているのであれば、
is supposed to increase crop yields
作物の収量が増加すると考えられています
can also reduce the godhead
神性を減らすこともできる
And that means we want to minimize the damage to gold
つまり、金へのダメージを最小限に抑えたいということです
nutrition that can also improve human health
人間の健康も改善できる栄養
The question is, are institutional plants really that safe?
問題は、施設用植物は本当に安全なのかということです。
there are two possibilities there are two you will worry about
可能性は 2 つあり、心配することは 2 つあります
The first one is whether it is practical or not safe
1つ目は実用的か安全ではないか
I think this should be safe
これは安全だと思います
because the food we eat every day
なぜなら、私たちが毎日食べる食べ物は、
Eating foreign DNA
外来DNAを食べる
Including the DNA of animals, plants and bacteria
動物、植物、細菌のDNAを含む
we eat them all
私たちはそれらをすべて食べます
And we humans have already
そして私たち人間はすでに
That is to say, it has been developed for almost 100,000 years.
つまり、10万年近くかけて発展してきたということです。
should be no problem
問題ないはずです
All the DNA you eat is digested
食べたDNAはすべて消化される
So this shouldn't be the main problem
したがって、これが主な問題ではないはずです
Practical and safe I think so far
今のところ実用的で安全だと思います
Didn't say you did genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えをしたとは言っていない
How about being poisoned after eating GMOs?
GMOを食べて中毒になったらどうですか？
This should be a non-scientific question
これは非科学的な質問であるはずです
It should mean that he and others
それは彼や他の人たちを意味するはずです
You're at about the same risk from eating other foods
他の食品を食べてもほぼ同じリスクにさらされます
I wouldn't say it's more dangerous
それがより危険だとは言いません
But there is one thing you should consider
しかし、考慮すべきことが 1 つあります
Will it have an impact on the ecological environment?
生態環境に影響はありますか?
you want me to say depend
あなたは私に依存してほしいと言いたいのですか
That is to say, it depends on what kind of genetically modified crops you make
つまり、どのような種類の遺伝子組み換え作物を作るかによって決まります。
Some will spread if, say, you are patterned
たとえば、パターン化されている場合、一部が広がる可能性があります
spreads far
遠くまで広がる
Then its patterns have certain properties
そして、そのパターンには特定の特性があります
likely to interbreed with other species.
他の種と交雑する可能性があります。
that maybe
それはもしかしたら
But the problem is we actually have the technology now
しかし問題は、私たちは今そのテクノロジーを実際に持っているということです
will control this
これを制御します
We can just say let you get that to that
それをやらせてくださいと言うだけです
The most important thing is that you passed it in.
最も重要なことは、あなたがそれを渡したことです。
We're doing this genetically modified crop
私たちはこの遺伝子組み換え作物を作っています
A few genes should be placed in the middle so that you can choose
選択できるように、いくつかの遺伝子を中央に配置する必要があります。
Those genes are usually associated with antibiotics
これらの遺伝子は通常、抗生物質と関連しています
can be antibiotics
抗生物質になる可能性があります
So you are afraid that this kind of thing will pollute the environment
つまり、この種のことが環境を汚染するのではないかと心配しているのですね
We now have the technology to remove it
今ではそれを除去する技術がある
After your genetically modified crops are made
遺伝子組み換え作物が作られた後
The gene you want goes in
欲しい遺伝子が入る
You can take these so-called vulture genes and remove them
これらのいわゆるハゲワシの遺伝子を取り出して取り除くことができます
So this should not be
したがって、これはあってはならない
It should mean that we can solve it now
それは今すぐ解決できることを意味するはずです
But I think we still need to have a
しかし、私たちはまだ必要があると思います
Rigorous evaluation process and management information
厳格な評価プロセスと管理情報
That is to say, if you have a
つまり、
That is to say, if there is a very strict procedure
つまり、非常に厳格な手順があれば、
I don't think this should be a major problem
これが大きな問題になるとは思わない
But we need a check system
でもチェック体制は必要だ
That's what I'm talking about now
それが今私が話していることです
It seems to mean that your biotechnology is used to make genetically modified crops
それはあなたのバイオテクノロジーが遺伝子組み換え作物を作るために使用されていることを意味しているようです
So I'm going to use a practical example now
それでは、実際の例を使用してみましょう
Just use the tunnel example to convince everyone
トンネルの例を使ってみんなを納得させてください
That is to say, genetically modified crops are only part of biotechnology.
つまり、遺伝子組み換え作物はバイオテクノロジーの一部にすぎません。
rather than all of it
全部というよりは
Then you if I hope that means you arrive
それなら、あなたが到着することを意味すると願っています
You can feel it after I say this
私がこれを言った後、あなたはそれを感じることができます
If you can flexibly apply biotechnology
バイオテクノロジーを柔軟に応用できれば
you should be able to do well then
そうすればうまくできるはずだ
than you mean you can
あなたができるというよりも
What you have to worry about is a lot more
あなたが心配しなければならないことはもっとたくさんあります
So what I'm going to say now is
だから私がこれから言おうとしているのは、
That is to say, how do we use quality-based breeding
つまり、品質に基づいた育種をどのように行うかということです。
To cultivate the quality of those saltwater waterways
海水の水路の質を高めるために
Then this salt water is actually a very important
この塩水は実はとても重要なものなのです
that agricultural problem
その農業問題
That world means agriculture every year
その世界では毎年農業が必要になります
The loss caused by pickling water will probably stand in vain
酸洗いによる損失はおそらく無駄になるだろう
That is to say especially in that
つまり、特にその点では
in that is to say the main river
つまり本流です
The place where there are floods and floods
洪水や洪水が起こる場所
this is the main problem
これが主な問題です
that unfortunately most of us
それは私たちのほとんどにとって残念なことです
the cultivated crop
栽培された作物
After spraying with pickled water, you will lack oxygen
漬け水を噴霧した後、波しぶきをかけると酸欠になります。
So most of the crops
つまり、ほとんどの作物は
can only live
そうやってしか生きられない
survive for a short time
短期間生き残る
Even if there are a lot of crops that will be flooded
たとえ水浸しになる作物がたくさんあったとしても
small amount of corn soybean
少量のトウモロコシ大豆
wheat sorghum
コムギソルガム
The flooded main do have a
浸水したメインには、
There is rice
お米があります
because you rice you can almost grow it in water
お米はほぼ水中でも栽培できるので、
But in fact, in the various strains of rice
しかし実際には、さまざまな品種の米で
It also has a different kind of collection for that flooded
洪水のための別の種類のコレクションもあります
Then this is an experiment done at the Philippine International Rice Research Center
これはフィリピン国際稲研究センターで行われた実験です
It combines two different strains
2つの異なる株を組み合わせたものです
The strain on the left is called FR-SERDIAN-A
左側の株は FR-SERDIAN-A と呼ばれます
Then the strain on the right
次に右側のひずみ
AR-SIXTIFOR is actually similar to Thai bananas
AR-SIXTIFORは実はタイのバナナに似ています
very popular in Southeast Asia
東南アジアで大人気
And it has a very high yield
そして非常に高い収率を誇ります
And you don't really need thinking
そして、本当に考える必要はありません
resistant
耐性のある
So in almost the whole of Southeast Asia are relying on
したがって、東南アジアのほぼ全体で、
They are all planted with the so-called AR-SIXTIFOR strain of rice
これらはすべて、このいわゆる AR-SIXTIFOR 株の米で植えられています。
The experiment they did was you take these two
彼らが行った実験は、この 2 つを摂取するというものでした
These two rice
この二つのご飯
Soak the whole thing in water, not just the roots
根元だけでなく全体を水に浸す
You put the whole spider in the water
クモを丸ごと水の中に入れると
After soaking for a week
一週間漬け込んだ後
you take the water away
あなたは水を奪います
another week
もう一週間
You can see that this basmati rice is dead
このバスマティライスは死んでいるのがわかります
This FR setting A is still peeled well
このFR設定Aはまだよく剥がれます
this is a pity
これは残念です
This FR setting A rice quality is not very good
このFR設定は米の品質があまり良くありません
not very tasty
あまり美味しくない
and it doesn't produce much
そしてそれはあまり生産しません
So farmers like rice
だから農家はお米が好きなんです
just intolerable to flooding
ただ洪水には耐えられない
In southeast Asia especially in India's Heng River Cape State
東南アジア、特にインドのヘンリバーケープ州
And this coal palace smoke water is a major problem
そしてこの石炭宮殿の煙水が大きな問題です
because every time it's summer
夏になるたびに
it has monshun creek
モンシュンクリークがあります
Just one cigarette lasts for several months
たった一本のタバコは数ヶ月間持続します
So this is the main question
これが主な質問です
That's at the top of the Heng River in that Nagara
それはあの長良の恒川の上流にある
You can see that there is a way
方法があることがわかります
This is their local
ここは彼らの地元です
and then later cultivated into cultivated roads
その後耕作され、耕作された道路になります
Then this is called Deep Waterway
それで、これは深層水路と呼ばれます
Then you can tell it's oily.
そうすると油っぽいのがわかります。
then this is a person
それならこれは人です
you can see these roads
これらの道が見えます
it can grow taller than a person
人の身長よりも大きくなることがあります
Then this Daozi
それからこの道子
Then your Dao is not a very good cultivation Dao.
それでは、あなたの道はあまり良い修煉道ではありません。
Because of its path, if you are planting
その道があるので、植えている場合は、
this is water
これは水です
if you drink hookah
水タバコを飲むなら
it has a reason
それには理由があります
It just grows taller than the river
川よりも高く成長するだけです
so it always has some leaves
だからいつも葉っぱがあるんだ
and cloth on the ground on the water
そして水の上の地面に布を置く
what good is that
それは何の良いことですか
Because of the effect of light ears, the silk protection cloth is oxygen
光耳の効果により、絹の保護布は酸素を含んでいます。
So you only need a part of your essence to be on the surface of the water
つまり、あなたのエッセンスの一部だけが水面にあればいいのです
The effect of the light ear
光耳の効果
You can make oxygen and you can make sugar
酸素も作れるし砂糖も作れる
So you have oxygen attack
つまり酸素攻撃を起こしているのです
Then your silk protection cloth will have oxygen again
そうすれば、シルク保護布に再び酸素が含まれます。
so it can be passed to
に渡すことができます
so it will live
それで生きられるだろう
But the problem is what to do when the water recedes
しかし問題は水が引いたらどうするかだ
it's because it grows too tall
身長が伸びすぎるからだよ
it just fell off
それは落ちただけです
You see we grow so short
私たちがとても短くなっているのがわかりますか
makes sense
意味がある
because it's going to knot and the knot is heavy
崩れやすく結び目が重いので
so it can't grow too tall
だから身長が伸びすぎない
And its coldness is very high
そしてその冷たさは非常に高いです
It all went through our old ancestors
すべては私たちの古い先祖を経て
Cultivated by President Yu
ユ社長が育てた
it's so short
とても短いです
makes sense
意味がある
It can bind so much water
非常に多くの水を結合できる
So if this raw water arrives
それでこの原水が届いたら
When the water recedes, it really falls down.
水が引くと本当に落ちてしまいます。
its a week or two later
それは1週間か2週間後です
it starts to grow roots from here again
ここからまた根が伸び始める
The problem is the process of this growth
問題はその成長過程だ
its only good thing is that it survives
唯一良いことは生き残ることだ
let it live not very well
あまりうまく生きられないようにしましょう
So it receives very little paper
そのため、受け取る紙はほとんどありません
So you're going to take this as
したがって、これを次のように受け取ることになります
its main source words
その主な出典の言葉
not sour
酸っぱくない
Which means you're unlikely to be able to live off of this
つまり、これでは生きていけない可能性が高い
Mongala countries those
モンガラ諸国の人々
so this is
それでこれは
The greenhouse of the Agricultural Department of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学農学部の温室
They planted this deep waterway
彼らはこの深い水路を植えました
Then this is to collect water
それから、これは水を集めるためです
That's about four meters tall
あれは高さ約4メートルだ
you can see this way
こうやって見ることができます
as long as you have water
水がある限り
it always grows on the water
いつも水の上に生える
It has grown to four meters now
今では4メートルにまで成長しました
more than three meters
3メートル以上
Then it should have a world record
そうすれば世界記録も出るはずだ
It seems to be seven or eight meters
7、8メートルはあるようです
in that
その中で
It's over there in India
インドのあそこだよ
there is a picture of this
これの写真があります
that so
まあまあ
Let's get these crops
これらの作物を手に入れましょう
classify a little
少し分類してみる
salt water resistant
耐塩水性
Afraid of salt water
塩水が怖い
then the waterway
それから水路
There is also a little bit of salt water
塩水も少しあります
And Sectivo
そしてセクティボ
then these two
それからこの二人
F-F-Sectivo
F-F-セクティボ
And this deep channel
そしてこの深いチャンネルは
will sell salt water
塩水を販売します
that so
まあまあ
First
初め
Actually you want
実はあなたが欲しいのは
if you want to leave
去りたいなら
your first question
あなたの最初の質問
That's why different crops
だから作物が違うんだよ
will have different water resistance
耐水性が異なります
That's because I'm a teacher
それは私が教師だからです
so i tried this
それで私はこれを試しました
Today's section is about science
今日のセクションは科学についてです
That is to say, it is related to the comparison made by our laboratory.
つまり、当研究室での比較に関わるものです。
I hope that means that if this doesn't work out,
これがうまくいかなかった場合は、
It's okay, wait a minute and you can ask me
大丈夫、ちょっと待って、聞いてもいいよ
But I should just keep it really simple
でも本当にシンプルにしておくべきだよ
Then all organisms lack oxygen and we need nutrients
その場合、すべての生物は酸素が不足し、栄養素が必要になります
Let's rejuvenate
若返ろう
when there is more oxygen
酸素が増えると
The main source of energy for you and us is from Prado
あなたと私たちの主なエネルギー源はプラドからです
aerobic respiration
好気呼吸
It generates 38 so-called ADPs
38 個のいわゆる ADP を生成します
That's where our cells' energy comes from
私たちの細胞のエネルギーはそこから来ます
Then if you are hypoxic
次に、低酸素症の場合
into the so-called anaerobic respiration
いわゆる嫌気呼吸に入る
That one glucose can only produce two ADP
1つのグルコースは2つのADPしか生成できない
there are two ways
2つの方法があります
That one is through the so-called lactic acid type
それはいわゆる乳酸タイプによるものです
one is alcoholic
一人はアルコール依存症です
Most of all animals have passed through the so-called
すべての動物のほとんどは、いわゆる
Once you are hypoxic
一旦低酸素状態になると
undergoes what is known as lactic acid fermentation
いわゆる乳酸発酵が起こります
so why are we afraid
それでなぜ私たちは恐れるのですか
That is to say, a stroke in the brain is a lack of oxygen in the brain cells.
つまり、脳卒中は脳細胞の酸素不足です。
why can't it last
なぜそれが続かないのか
because
なぜなら
Animals can only do so-called lactic acid flower effects
動物はいわゆる乳酸菌フラワー効果しかできません
this is sour
これは酸っぱいです
So you suddenly acidify the cytoplasm
それで細胞質を突然酸性化します
the cell dies
細胞が死ぬ
dead in 20 minutes
20分以内に死亡
brain cells die
脳細胞が死ぬ
So why is swelling so severe?
では、なぜ腫れがこれほどひどいのでしょうか？
Plants are a little smarter
植物はもう少し賢い
It will also take the lactic acid flower effect at the beginning
初めは乳酸菌フラワー効果もかかります
But once its cytoplasmic Ph
しかし、細胞質の Ph が上昇すると、
to 5.5
5.5まで
It will transform into a flower effect called alcoholic type
アルコール系というフラワーエフェクトに変化します
Sexualize it with alcohol and it will seep out
アルコールで性化すると滲み出てくる
Most plant cells can survive in the absence of oxygen
ほとんどの植物細胞は酸素がなくても生存できます
can live for a while
しばらくは生きていける
So the first biological anoxic
最初の生物学的無酸素症
Oxygen free
無酸素
always oxygen free
常に無酸素状態
second word in plant words
植物言葉の 2 番目の単語
This is a cut surface of the root tip of a hardtail
ハードテイルの根元先端の切断面です
This is a normal hardtail tip
これは通常のハードテイルティップです
You can see it this one we call Cortic rare
ご覧のとおり、これはコルティックレアと呼ばれるものです
just very evenly
とても均等に
Cell size is successful
セルサイズは成功しました
it's about the same and it's tight
ほぼ同じで、きついです
Then you take the liquid that has been along the water for 18 hours
次に、18時間水に沿って放置された液体を採取します。
you make a cross section of it
あなたはそれの断面図を作ります
Then you can see that it has many
すると、たくさんあることがわかります
In fact, this is where the cells die.
実際、ここで細胞が死ぬのです。
that forms a tube
管を形成するもの
one looks like a big circle
一つは大きな円のように見えます
If you look at it, this is the cross section
見てみると断面図です
Then if you fancy the section
このセクションが気に入ったら
This is actually a tube
実はこれチューブなんです
Then I said before that the action of light will create oxygen
次に、光の作用で酸素が生成されると前に言いました。
So most plants have this ability
つまり、ほとんどの植物はこの能力を持っています
That is to say, once its roots are flooded
つまり、根が氾濫すると、
it wants to form a trachea
気管を形成したいのです
Let it have more oxygen
酸素をもっと取り込みましょう
but the problem is that if the corn
しかし問題は、トウモロコシが
Actually you drown it for 36 hours and it dies
実際に36時間溺死させると死んでしまいます
So while corn wants to do this
トウモロコシがこれをやりたいと思っている間、
it's too late
もう手遅れです
Because when your adversity comes
なぜなら、逆境が来たとき、
it's too late for you to do it
あなたがそれをするには遅すぎます
That
それか
so
それで
but
しかし
water arrived
水が到着しました
Our strategy says that under normal conditions, you are born with tubular tissue
私たちの戦略によれば、通常の状態では、人は管状組織を持って生まれます。
If you cut the root of the water channel, there will be this kind of tubular tissue
水路の根元を切るとこのような管状組織が出てきます
So it is inherently slightly water-alongable
したがって、本質的にわずかに水親和性があります
So why can we, we can put the waterway inside the water
ではなぜ、水路を水の中に入れることができるのでしょうか？
But you can’t explain the villager, the FR setting class and the deep water channel
でも村人とかFR設定クラスとか深層水路とか説明できないよな
Because all three of them have this ability, all three of them can breathe anaerobically
3人ともこの能力を持っているので、3人とも嫌気呼吸ができる
will also form the tubular tissue
管状組織も形成します
Why is HR60 still not CUT, this FR setting is still CUT
なぜHR60はまだCUTではないのですか、このFR設定はまだCUTです
This is also very CUT, so the International Waterway Research Center wants to know
これも非常に斬新なので、国際水路研究センターは知りたいと思っています
Why is this villager different from FR settings? What is the difference between them?
この村人はなぜFR設定と違うのでしょうか?何が違うのでしょうか?
They've been doing it since 1980
彼らは1980年からそれをやっています
sent them 20 years
彼らに20年を送った
they finally found that is to say
彼らはついにそれを発見した、つまり
In total five genes are
合計5つの遺伝子は、
That is to say, let this FR setting be able to resist flooding
つまり、この FR 設定がフラッディングに耐えられるようにします。
but there is one most important
しかし、最も重要なことが一つあります
That is, as long as you have this gene
つまり、この遺伝子がある限り、
He's about 80 percent water resistant
約80パーセントの耐水性がある
But he only knows which one to set
しかし、彼はどれを設定すべきかを知っているだけです
he doesn't know what gene
彼はどの遺伝子か知りません
So he has no way to want to be the general manager
だから彼はゼネラルマネージャーになりたいわけがない
At this time, it means that he was born in 2000
この時点では2000年生まれということになります
It was in 1996
1996年のことでした
At that time, the so-called wedding paper pre-completion technology
当時はいわゆるウェディングペーパー事前完成技術
has become very mature
とても成熟しました
so there are a few
だからいくつかあります
the University of California
カリフォルニア大学
Riverside and this
リバーサイドとこれ
The family background of the two groups of Dennis Marriage School This team
デニス・マリッジ・スクールの２つのグループの家族背景 このチーム
It took them five years to find the gene for flood resistance
洪水耐性の遺伝子を見つけるのに5年かかった
This flood resistance gene actually
実はこの洪水耐性遺伝子は
Quite simply, because of the so-called biotechnology
簡単に言えば、いわゆるバイオテクノロジーのせいです。
Now the so-called molecular domain species actually has several methods
さて、いわゆる分子ドメイン種には実際にはいくつかの方法があります
Then I will only introduce to you one of the more commonly used methods.
次に、より一般的に使用される方法の 1 つだけを紹介します。
Then the method is, for example, this is you
そうすると、このメソッドは、たとえば、これはあなたです
The FR design is also resistant to vaping, but it is not very good at keeping the output low
FR 設計はベーピングにも耐性がありますが、出力を低く保つのはあまり得意ではありません。
Then this is the so-called Thai sweet potato
これがいわゆるタイのスイートポテトです
It is not resistant to vaping, so it says but it yields very well, and the rice quality is also very good
耐病性が無いと書いてありますが、収量が非常に良く、米質も非常に良いです。
So what do you most want to do as a field breeder?
では、フィールドブリーダーとして一番やりたいことは何ですか？
Let it go to the end, for example, this is an anti-smoke machine
最後までやりましょう、たとえばこれは禁煙マシンです
It hopes that in the end it will be planted by your last domain
最終的にはあなたの最後のドメインに植えられることを望んでいます
all its machines
そのすべてのマシン
All of them are the Xiangwu machine, except for the smoke-resistant machine
耐煙機を除いてすべて Xiangwu 機です
It's Qingben from this anti-smoke water
この防煙水の清本です
This Yanze is actually very simple
このYanzeは実はとてもシンプルです
You are the first one to compare the flood resistance and non-flood resistance
洪水に対する耐性と非洪水に対する耐性を比較したのはあなたが初めてです。
After hybridization, it will have the so-called
ハイブリダイゼーション後は、いわゆる
recommendation that recommendation it will exchange chromosomes
染色体を交換することを推奨する
Then you can choose from among your offspring
そうすれば自分の子孫の中から選ぶことができる
It is flood resistant
洪水に強いです
after you have this
これを持った後
You can hand it back to this white guy again
もう一度この白人に戻ってもいいよ
If so
もしそうなら
It will start to replace these blue ones step by step
この青いものは段階的に置き換えられ始めます
replace to the end
最後まで置き換える
That is to say, you see that you have to recross almost eight times.
つまり、ほぼ 8 回再交差する必要があることがわかります。
you can put other genes
他の遺伝子を入れることもできる
All are the genes of this Thai countryman
すべてはこのタイ人の同胞の遺伝子だ
Except this is the flood resistance gene
これが洪水耐性遺伝子であることを除いて
This word in the Lord is very simple
主のこの言葉はとてもシンプルです
it's not that easy
そんなに簡単じゃないよ
There is no way for them to do the traditional one
彼らには従来の方法を行う方法はありません
because they have no way of knowing
彼らには知る由もないから
Which gene is this
これはどの遺伝子ですか
that do
それはする
With the marriage paper biology, we can have each chromosome
結婚論文の生物学を使えば、次のことが可能になります。
Find it is what we call a wedding paper label
それは私たちが結婚式の紙ラベルと呼んでいるものです
So you just do some simple tests
それで、いくつかの簡単なテストを行うだけです
you will know
あなたは知るだろう
For example, you are a hybrid, you do a few simple tests
たとえば、あなたはハイブリッド型で、いくつかの簡単なテストを実行します。
You can know whether your section is blue or white
自分のセクションが青か白かを知ることができます
There is absolutely no way to do this in our traditional way.
従来の方法ではこれを行う方法はまったくありません。
if you don't have so called biotechnology
いわゆるバイオテクノロジーを持っていない場合
you can't do it
それはできません
It is because of this technology
この技術のおかげで
They quickly found the technology within five years
彼らは 5 年以内にそのテクノロジーを素早く発見しました
This is from the International Watercourse Organization
これは国際水路機関からのものです
the one on their website
彼らのウェブサイトにあるもの
You can see that this channel is twelve chromosomes
このチャネルは 12 個の染色体であることがわかります
Then this is the FR setting that will resist smoke and water
これが煙や水に強いFRセッティングです
You see it's backcrossing and backcrossing a few times
何度か戻し交配を繰り返しているのがわかります
In the end they were like this for two years
結局2年間もこんな感じだった
Because Huili Waterfront has three goods a year
回里ウォーターフロントには年に3回の商品があるため
So he seriously backcrossed them for two years and they found
そこで彼は2年間真剣に戻し交配を行ったところ、次のことが分かりました。
And of course some tests
そしてもちろんいくつかのテストも
After finding this, you can easily find this season because of the molecular mark
これを見つけたら分子マークでこの季節も簡単に見つけられる
This season so they spent half a year
今シーズンは半年を費やしたので
This is what they do traditionally
これが彼らが伝統的にやっていることです
This is the most popular waterway in Mangara
マンガラで最も人気のある水路です
but afraid of salt water
でも塩水は怖い
This is after salt water
こちらは塩水後です
This is the FR setting class I mentioned earlier.
先ほど述べたFR設定クラスです。
this is a hybrid
これはハイブリッドです
You see it backcrossed twice and five times
2回と5回戻し交配されているのがわかります
It is equal to the result of ten times, you can see it
10回の結果と同じです、ご覧のとおりです
it will make it salt water resistant
耐塩水になります
This is the so-called molecular domain species
これはいわゆる分子ドメイン種です。
But it only takes half a year for you to use the genetic modification method
でも遺伝子組み換え法なら半年しかかからない
because they found the gene
彼らは遺伝子を見つけたから
They are called Savwan A
彼らはサブワンAと呼ばれます
This gene is in the FR setting class
この遺伝子はFR設定クラスにあります
Just inside the Thai mud
タイの泥の中にいます
Determine if the channel will be salt water resistant
チャンネルが塩水耐性があるかどうかを決定する
the gene they found
彼らが見つけた遺伝子
Put it in Thai incense mud for half a year
タイの香泥に半年漬ける
as you can see it's very resistant to salt water
ご覧のとおり、塩水に非常に強いです
Then they, the three of us, they also took our Tainong No. 67
それから彼ら、私たち3人も私たちのタイノン67号を受け取りました。
Tainong No. 67 is the most important one in Taiwan
Tainong No. 67 は台湾で最も重要なものです
You're on the west coast and most of the east coast
あなたは西海岸と東海岸の大部分にいます
the one that came out
出てきたもの
That our cultivation way in Taiwan
台湾での私たちの栽培方法
They are all descendants of Tainong 67
彼らは皆、タイノン67の子孫です。
Then they are also very afraid of flooding on Tainong 67
そして彼らはタイノン67の洪水も非常に恐れている
Then they also released the first half
その後、前半部分もリリースされました
Natai Nong 67 now also has anti-flooding subsidence
ナタイ ノン 67 にも洪水防止の沈下が施されています
You can get around at the International Watercourse Organization
国際水路機関で移動できます
This is because the IHO Research Center is
なぜなら、IHOリサーチセンターは、
A research center under the auspices of the United Nations
国連の後援の下にある研究センター
So you need none of these races for money
つまり、お金のためにこれらのレースは必要ありません
means no profit
利益がないことを意味する
That is to say, everyone can
つまり誰でもできる
So actually that means
つまり、実際にはそれは意味します
They've been doing this for twenty years
彼らはこれを20年も続けている
That is, the progress has been rapid in the last five years.
つまり、この5年間で急速に進歩したということです。
that is let them just say
それは彼らに言わせてください
they did some experiments
彼らはいくつかの実験をしました
Because besides being practical, you
なぜなら、実用的であるだけでなく、
You now find this Thai township you will resist flooding
あなたは今、洪水に耐えられるこのタイの町を見つけました
Then let's make some machines
それでは機械を作ってみましょう
why do you want to ask
なぜ聞きたいのですか
Why is he resistant to flooding
なぜ洪水に強いのか
This FR is set to resist flooding
この FR はフラッディングに耐えるように設定されています
Then you will find
そうすれば見つかります
These strains that are not resistant to flooding
浸水に耐性のないこれらの株
when it is flooded
浸水したとき
it will continue to grow
それは成長し続けるだろう
There's a downside to continuing to grow
成長を続けることにはマイナス面もある
it consumes energy
エネルギーを消費します
so it quickly puts its
それですぐに置きます
That stored nutrient is used up
蓄えられた栄養素が使い果たされてしまう
so you flood it a week later
それで一週間後に水浸しになります
you take it out again
あなたはまたそれを取り出します
it dies
それは死ぬ
Then this FR setting
そしてこのFR設定
or your jasmine rice
またはあなたのジャスミンライス
Coupled with this anti-flooding machine
この浸水防止機と組み合わせると
once you flood it
一度浸水してしまうと
it stops growing
成長が止まる
It only maintains its most basic metabolism
最も基礎的な代謝のみを維持します
Then it saves a lot of energy
そうすると、かなりのエネルギーが節約されます
so once you put it
それで、一度それを置くと
when you flood it
浸水したとき
You submerge it for another month
さらに一ヶ月水に沈めると
it won't die yet
まだ死なないだろう
you take it out again
あなたはまたそれを取り出します
as long as it can continue the action of light
光の作用を続ける限り
it survives again
それはまた生き残る
so it's a strategy
だからそれは戦略だ
It should be regarded as a magnetic strategy
それは磁気戦略と見なされるべきです
Even if you use salt water, it will not move, and then it can be replenished for a long time
塩水を使っても動かず、長期間補える
Animals also have this disadvantaged strategy, the tortoise
動物にもこの不利な戦略があります、カメ
There are some turtles, it can't breathe for a long time
亀が何匹かいます、長い間呼吸ができません
The main thing about it is that it shuts down almost all of its metabolism
重要なことは、代謝のほぼすべてを停止させることです。
So animals and plants have this Making
つまり、動物や植物にはこのような仕組みがあるのです
Then you have to ask, the deep water channel, it seems that because of its deep water channel, it must not stop
それからあなたは尋ねなければなりません、深層水路、その深層水路のために止めてはいけないようです
The deep channel is actually used for this or that
ディープチャネルは実際にはあれこれに使用されます
I think I'll just skip this
これはスキップしようと思います
The mechanism of the deep channel is just the opposite of this one
ディープチャンネルの仕組みはこれとは全く逆です
it is
それはです
This FR setting class it is salt water it does not move
このFRセッティングクラスはソルト水では動きません
Even if the salt water, this Thai villager who is resistant to salt water is
たとえ塩水であっても、塩水に強いこのタイの村人は、
It continues to grow, but it doesn't grow fast enough so it can't escape the water
成長し続けますが、成長速度が遅いため、水から逃れることができません。
that this
これは
So the raw water channel will make the giant gas grow, once it is sprayed to flood water, it will grow faster
したがって、原水路は巨大なガスを成長させ、洪水に噴霧すると、より速く成長します
So when we do molecular biology, we go back and ask
したがって、分子生物学を行うとき、私たちは戻って尋ねます。
That is to say, what is the mechanism?
つまり、どのような仕組みになっているのでしょうか？
Then you can know that this research is very good
そうすれば、この研究が非常に優れていることがわかります
It uses exactly the same metabolic pathway
まったく同じ代謝経路を使用します
That is to say, this one is its main response when it is flooded.
つまり、これが浸水時の主な反応です。
There's going to be a residual suction, and then it's going to be a chain of
残留吸引が発生し、それが連鎖的に発生します。
Then this thorn will make your cells continue to divide, and then continue to grow
そうすれば、このとげによって細胞は分裂し続け、成長し続けることになります。
The section in the middle is the road taken by Thai villagers.
真ん中のセクションはタイの村人が通った道です。
That is to say, it does not change, and it will continue to grow when it is flooded, so it is
つまり、変化することはなく、浸水しても成長し続けるので、
Then this is set by that FR
次に、これはその FR によって設定されます
The way it goes is that it turns off its own metabolic records
その仕組みは、自身の代謝記録を無効にすることです
so it doesn't grow so it survives
だから成長しないから生き残る
Then its mechanism is to use this growth technology
そしてその仕組みは、この成長技術を利用することです
it turns it off when it's flooded
浸水すると電源が切れます
stop plant cells from growing
植物細胞の成長を止める
flooded to
に浸水した
It also controls the same metabolic pathway
同じ代謝経路も制御します
it just turned upside down
それはちょうどひっくり返った
It allows this growth technique to produce more
この成長技術により、より多くの生産物を生産できるようになります。
It makes more when it's flooded
浸水するともっと儲かる
so you can tell
だからあなたは言うことができます
The place where the evolution temple is
進化神殿がある場所
In the same way, if you correct it and correct it, the effect will be the same.
同じように修正しても修正しても効果は同じです。
are flood-resistant waterways
洪水に強い水路です
So doing this kind of experiment is very rewarding
なので、このような実験をするのはとてもやりがいがあります
because you have practical value
あなたには実用的な価値があるから
because you can improve that is
それは改善できるからです
Now the rice is already in the ashes of the populace
今、米はすでに民衆の灰になっている
It should be released next year
来年発売されるはず
The Mengala strain I mentioned earlier
先ほど紹介したメンガラ株
It will also be promoted in Mongara
モンガラでもプロモーションを開始
How local farmers grow
地元の農家がどのように成長するか
The most important thing is this pre-made rice
一番重要なのはこの作り置きご飯です
Its yield and quality are the same as those of the original strain.
収量、品質ともに原株と同等です。
They have been experimenting for three years
彼らは3年間実験を続けてきた
know now
今知っています
So this gift is
そこで今回のプレゼントは、
have a practical use
実用的な用途がある
but in science
しかし科学では
You mean in basic research
基礎研究ということですね
You also get a great deal
お得な特典もございます
because of this
このため
just to let you know this
これをお知らせするためだけに
so-called molecular mechanisms
いわゆる分子機構
That's what we do
それが私たちのやることです
The problems that basic researchers are doing
基礎研究者が取り組んでいる問題
so maybe
かもね
then you can ask
それから尋ねることができます
Then we can not use this technology
そうなるとこの技術は使えなくなります
to make a super channel
スーパーチャンネルを作るには
For example, if you start from the natural
たとえば、ナチュラルな状態から始めると、
inside wild road
ワイルドロードの中
or various materials
またはさまざまな素材
it has this
それはこれを持っています
For example, it looks very tax-heavy
たとえば、税金が非常に重そうに見えます。
And it looks so big on you
そしてそれはあなたにはとても大きく見えます
And it's anti-algorithm
そしてそれはアンチアルゴリズムです
or smoke resistant
または耐煙性
it's being done now
それは今行われています
It uses this molecular labeling method
この分子標識法を使用します
take it
それを取る
want to put it
それを置きたい
That is to say it delivers this
つまりこれを提供します
one
一個
for example for example
たとえばたとえば
Our Tainong No. 67
私たちのタイノン No. 67
Maybe we'll go both ways in the future
もしかしたら将来的には両方の道を歩むことになるかもしれない
If this method
この方法なら
then you can just say
それならあなたはただ言うことができます
Opponents of GMOs probably you can reach a goose shoe
GMO の反対者はおそらくガチョウの靴に手が届くでしょう
Because this method you don't use the base modification
この方法では基本的な変更を使用しないため、
Although your end result is exactly the same
最終結果はまったく同じですが、
But this is not every crop you can do
しかし、これができるすべての作物ではありません
because you want to do this
あなたがこれをしたいから
First of all, you have to have a lot of what we call seed relationship
まず第一に、いわゆるシード関係をたくさん持っている必要があります
So why is biodiversity so important?
では、なぜ生物多様性はそれほど重要なのでしょうか?
because you want to see what sex
性別が知りたいから
you must have this gene
あなたはこの遺伝子を持っているに違いありません
In this species you have this gene
この種にはこの遺伝子があります
You can use this method
この方法を使用できます
if you don't
そうしないと
For example, the bananas you mentioned earlier
たとえば、先ほどお話ししたバナナです。
It doesn't have such a good relationship at all, what should you do?
あまり良い関係ではないのですが、どうすればいいでしょうか？
Then your GM crops are the only way
その場合、GM作物が唯一の方法です
So to say this from my point of view is to say
私の観点からこれを言うと、
If it means that the genetic modification is not genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えが遺伝子組み換えではないということであれば
Up to now, I personally think that it is not a scientific problem.
今のところ、個人的にはそれが科学的な問題だとは思っていません。
It's about political issues
政治問題に関するものです
that is
あれは
That is to say, the problem of acceptance in our society
つまり、私たちの社会における受け入れの問題です。
We scientists are responsible for this
私たち科学者にはこれに対する責任があります
We need to talk to the public
私たちは国民と話す必要がある
That is, if we could have more conversations with that
つまり、もっと会話できたら
Just face this method with an honest attitude of comparison
比較するという正直な姿勢でこの方法に向き合ってください。
Maybe it means that some of our future crops
おそらくそれは、私たちの将来の作物の一部が、
We can use sense to change
感覚を使って変えることができる
Some of you will feel that this technique is
このテクニックは、と感じる人もいるでしょう。
Then of course we use the words of this so-called molecular art
もちろん、私たちはこのいわゆる分子芸術の言葉を使います。
that's it
それでおしまい
seems to mean
という意味のようです
This biotechnology can be used in this respect
このバイオテクノロジーはこの点で使用できます
Then I am now at the end of my person, that is to say
それでは私は今、人間としての終わりに来ています、つまり
In fact, I have been in the US for 30 years and only came back in 2008
実際、私は米国に 30 年間住んでいて、2008 年に戻ってきたばかりです。
Then I have been in the past almost 4 years
それから私は過去約4年間に渡って
That is to say, we have direct contact with Taiwan's agricultural sector
つまり、私たちは台湾の農業分野と直接コンタクトしています。
Then the following is my personal opinion
それでは以下は私の個人的な意見です
I think it means that our biotechnology can be used in
私たちのバイオテクノロジーがこんなところで使えるということだと思います。
Our government actually sees the importance of this biotechnology
私たちの政府は実際にこのバイオテクノロジーの重要性を認識しています
So he proposed the so-called six emerging industries
そこで彼はいわゆる新興6産業を提案した。
There is the so-called golden agriculture and the biotechnology industry, the strength industry
いわゆる黄金の農業とバイオテクノロジー産業、体力産業があります。
This is more or less related to agricultural biotechnology
これは多かれ少なかれ農業バイオテクノロジーに関連しています
Our government has also created an interministerial so-called Agricultural Biotechnology Advancement Program
私たちの政府はまた、省庁間のいわゆる農業バイオテクノロジー推進プログラムを創設しました。
There is a goal in this plan
この計画には目標があります
In fact, want to help our country's economy
実際、私たちの国の経済を助けたい
That is to say, to increase the output value of the agricultural biotechnology industry
つまり、農業バイオテクノロジー産業の生産額を増やすことです。
but of course it's important
でももちろんそれは重要です
But is biotechnology only used once?
しかし、バイオテクノロジーは一度しか使われないのでしょうか?
Then I think there is another aspect of biotechnology besides this.
それから、バイオテクノロジーにはこれ以外にも別の側面があると思います。
important task
重要な任務
this task is
このタスクは
Because of the problems we face in Taiwan's agriculture
台湾の農業が直面する問題のため
It's not a matter of value
それは価値観の問題ではない
Because of your agricultural bioindustry
農業バイオ産業のおかげで
You will never your output value will never exceed the electronics industry
あなたの出力値がエレクトロニクス業界を超えることは決してありません
But it's actually more important than that
でも実際にはそれよりも重要なのです
There are so-called economists in our country
私たちの国にはいわゆる経済学者がいます
That is to say, in that because of the rice
つまり、お米のせいで
The problem of subsidizing farmers
農家への補助金の問題
Need to say that rice is so cheap
お米がとても安いと言うべきです
So cheap, just import them all
安いから全部輸入すればいいだけ
we don't plant
私たちは植えません
This sounds a little bit
これは少し聞こえる
Yes Just Say About the Basic Concepts of Food Security
はい、食料安全保障の基本概念について言ってください
Economist who knows nothing
何も知らない経済学者
because the world think about it
世界がそう思っているから
So rice is not a problem of greedy cats
つまり、ご飯は貪欲な猫の問題ではありません
not a commodity
商品ではありません
Everyone, think about it, is there a country in the world?
皆さん、考えてみてください、世界に国はありますか？
Said to grow rice for sale
米を作って販売しているという
rice to sell
売るお米
You can't find it. Countries around the world are successful in producing rice, so it is sold to other countries
世界中の国が米の生産に成功し、他の国に販売されています
No country says that I specialize in selling rice, and the United States specializes in selling corn, and it doesn’t need to love corn
私が米を売るのが専門だなんてどこの国も言っていないし、米国はトウモロコシを売るのが専門であり、トウモロコシを愛する必要はない
Because the corn it exports is not for food, it is eaten when it loses all, and the corn in it is used for other purposes
輸出するトウモロコシは食用ではないので、なくなったら食べて、中のトウモロコシは他の用途に使われる
So soybeans are also this and that, but rice is not a commodity
だから大豆もあれこれだけど、米は商品じゃない
Once you say that there are some factors that affect the rice production, now Thailand will take it back and it will not export
米の生産に影響を与える要因があると言ったら、今度はタイが米を引き取り、輸出しなくなる
So we don’t want to grow rice in Taiwan because it doesn’t know about food security.
したがって、台湾は食料安全保障を知らないので、私たちは台湾で米を作りたくないのです。
That is to say, there is also this TU change at this level, so I will talk about these two
つまり、このレベルでもTUの変更があるので、この2つについて話します
As for the sustainable use, I think President Wang Wu just said that our middle camp will probably slow down. In fact, we are already doing it, and we will do it in the future.
持続可能な利用に関しては、先ほど王呉総統が中陣営のペースは鈍化するだろうとおっしゃったと思いますが、実際、既に実施しており、今後も実施する予定です。
Let's just expand this area
このエリアを拡張してみましょう
Then why do I say that food security is very important
では、なぜ私は食料安全保障が非常に重要だと言えるのでしょうか。
Because Taiwan's food independence was in 2008
台湾の食糧独立は2008年だったから
About 32% to 33%
約32%～33%
So far this year, 30% of it has been determined
今年はこれまでにその30％が決定済み
shares
株式
Don't say we have enough water
水が足りているとは言わないでください
We import a lot of stocks
大量の在庫品を輸入しております
use it for other purposes
他の目的に使用する
We now have less than 30% of our autonomy
現在、私たちの自治権は 30% 未満です
world
世界
Europe
ヨーロッパ
U.S.
私たち。
they subsidize their farmers
彼らは農家に補助金を出します
kind
親切
grow grain
種穀物
we subsidize our farmers
私たちは農家に補助金を出します
don't plant
植えないでください
Nasyune
那修根
don't want
不要
Don’t think that pruning roots is cultivating land
根を剪定することが土地を耕すことだと思わないでください
After a long time of pruning
長い時間をかけて剪定を行った後、
where you will
どこに行きますか
would be useless
役に立たないでしょう
because no one to take care of
世話してくれる人がいないから
you will have soon
すぐに手に入るでしょう
yes there is that
はい、それはあります
The quality of the soil will become very poor
土の質がかなり悪くなる
and this
この
The other one is that many of us
もう 1 つは、私たちの多くが
The excellent agricultural land becomes what I call a dog house in Yilan
宜蘭では優良な農地が犬小屋になる
It's like a farmhouse, a small farmhouse that even dogs can't live in.
農家のようなもので、犬も住めないような小さな農家です。
Our farmland is constantly being lost
私たちの農地は絶えず失われています
The worst thing is that Taiwan is not a miscellaneous grain that cannot be grown
最悪なのは台湾が栽培できない雑穀ではないことだ
we had twenty years ago
20年前にもありました
But because Taiwan's land chick Yale replaced our miscellaneous grains with corn and soybeans, we needed special varieties.
しかし、台湾の陸ひよこエール大学が雑穀をトウモロコシや大豆に置き換えたため、特別な品種が必要になりました。
All the people we pre-planted are lost because our government does not plant them ourselves
私たちの政府が自分たちで植えないので、私たちが事前に植えた人々は全員失われます
Those of us who preseeded are all lost
プレシードしていた人たちは全員失われてしまった
Then you have to turn back and say that now because the feed is very expensive, we are now saying that we will start growing our own grains
それからあなたは引き返して、飼料が非常に高価なので、私たちは今、自分たちで穀物を栽培し始めると言っていると言わなければなりません。
We need to retrain our pre-seeds not those of us who do molecular biology
私たちは分子生物学を行う私たちではなく、プレシードを再訓練する必要がある
It’s about pre-planting in the front. We don’t have these skills. Most of the people who don’t have high school
前面に事前に植栽することです。私たちにはそのようなスキルがありません。高校を卒業していない人のほとんどは、
And everyone is in their seventies now
そしてもうみんな70代です
So it will increase, this is our food security
だからそれは増えるだろう、これが私たちの食糧安全保障だ
Because once you have any situation that affects food production
食糧生産に影響を与えるような状況が発生すると、
Let's not look at such a low production value
そんな低い生産額は見ないでください
You can survive without a computer
パソコンがなくても生きていける
I don't have rice to eat, I'll see what to do
食べるご飯がないのでどうするか考えてみます
So food security is a big problem for Taiwan's agriculture
食料安全保障は台湾の農業にとって大きな問題だ
Another company not far away
遠くない別の会社
Everyone thinks maybe it means softening for 100 years
たぶんそれは100年間軟化することを意味すると誰もが思っています
only increase a degree or two
ほんの1、2度だけ
Will it really affect agriculture?
本当に農業に影響が出るのでしょうか？
So I'm also asking this question
それで私もこの質問をしています
So I'm asking this question now
それで今この質問をしています
Will corporate changes really affect Taiwan's crops?
企業の変革は本当に台湾の農作物に影響を与えるのだろうか？
The first one is that I have tweeted with many farmers in Taiwan.
1つ目は、台湾の多くの農家とツイートしたことです。
There are also many agricultural transformation factories in Taiwan
台湾には農業改造工場もたくさんあります
They are directly lower limit and farmers
彼らは直接の下限と農民です
Our rice has three major diseases
私たちのお米には三大病気があります
white leaf mushroom disease
白葉きのこ病
Dao Le disease
ダオレー病
The other one is called dragon mushroom disease
もう一つはドラゴンキノコ病と呼ばれるものです
Dragon mushroom disease has no effect
ドラゴンキノコ病は効果なし
There is no medicine, but it is relatively rare in Taiwan
薬はありませんが、台湾では比較的まれです
There are medicines for Bai Ye Gu's disease and Dao Le's disease
バイイェグ病とダオレ病の薬があります
But our farmers often spray pesticides until they pass out
しかし、私たちの農家は気を失うまで殺虫剤を散布することがよくあります。
It's because of the medicine they're going to spill
薬がこぼれるからだよ
these two
この二つ
We have some strains in Taiwan
台湾にもいくつかの株があります
It is the strain introduced from Taiwan 67 Medicine
台湾67医学から導入された株です
against certain bacteria
特定の細菌に対して
So our farms and factories have their tasks
したがって、私たちの農場と工場にはそれぞれの仕事があります
just to tell the farmers
農家に伝えるだけ
For example, which strain of rice do you want to plant in the next few years?
たとえば、今後数年以内にどの品種の米を植えたいと考えていますか?
You can compare against Dowle's disease
ダウル病と比較できます
Comparable against white night disease
白夜病に匹敵する
They told me it seems like the last ten years
ここ10年のことのようだと彼らは言った
I said before that you promote a strain
前にも言いましたが、あなたは緊張を促進します
about ten years
約10年
They feel that the past ten years
彼らはこの10年間をこう感じている
That is to say, this cycle is getting shorter and shorter
つまり、このサイクルはどんどん短くなっていきます
their speculation is that
彼らの推測はそれです
Because of the increase in average temperature
平均気温の上昇により
The speed of this evolution is accelerated
その進化のスピードは加速する
is this real
これは本当ですか
so you're going to explore this
それであなたはこれについて話し合うつもりですか
another this problem is very serious, because no one will do it for us
もう一つ、この問題は非常に深刻です、なぜなら誰も私たちの代わりにやってくれないからです
Because Taiwan is here, this is the dimension of the Yangtze River
ここは台湾だから長江の次元だ
All the countries south of the Yangtze River speak the second language, called Indica
長江以南の国はすべて、インディカと呼ばれる第二言語を話します。
Because it is a subtropical species
亜熱帯種なので
The strain north of the Yangtze River is considered to be a relatively temperate strain, called Japongi
長江以北の株はジャポンギと呼ばれる比較的温帯な株と考えられています。
Taiwan was occupied by the Japanese for 50 years, so the Japanese developed a
台湾は50年間日本軍に占領されていたため、日本軍が開発した
This strain of red rice means that we are a large temperate species in a subtropical country
この赤米の品種は、私たちが亜熱帯の国に住む大型の温帯種であることを意味します。
If you grow like this, your germs will be completely different from others
このように成長すると、あなたの細菌は他の細菌とはまったく異なります
That is to say, Professor Wang Qiangsheng of Chung Hsing University
つまり、中興大学の王強生教授です。
He introduced 21 strains from the International Waterway Center, which are resistant to 21 kinds of bacteria
国際水路センターから21種類の細菌に耐性のある21株を紹介した。
The farm collects the bacteria of white leaf mushroom disease from all over Taiwan
農場は台湾全土から白葉茸病の菌を集めています
he took three whole parties
彼は3つのパーティーを丸ごと占領した
including eleven none
11 なしを含む
Three fungi of white leaf mushroom disease in Taiwan
台湾の白葉茸病の 3 つの菌類
Then we sequence the three bacteria
次に、3 つの細菌の配列を決定します。
I found out that you use this Pingtung as the boundary condition
この屏東を境界条件として使っていることが分かりました
The east comes from the Philippines
東はフィリピンから来た
The west side is more similar to Japan and South Korea
西側は日本と韓国に似ています
But he has evolved his own set of chances of healing
しかし、彼は治癒の可能性を独自に進化させました
so we don't do it ourselves
だから自分たちではやらない
no one will do it for you
誰もあなたの代わりにやってくれません
Because our bacteria are different from others
私たちの細菌は他の細菌とは異なるため
So now Professor Wang Qiangsen uses this
そこで今、王強森教授はこれを使用しています
With Tailong No. 67, he gave it to
Tailong No.67 で、彼はそれを与えました。
Give someone to find out who can resist
誰かに抵抗できる人を見つけてもらいましょう
Rice strains of white leaf mushroom disease in Taiwan
私たちの台湾における白葉茸病の米株
then we are doing this now
それなら私たちは今これをやっています
So this has something to do with the warming
これは温暖化と関係があるのですね
Because you if the experiment we're doing right now is
なぜなら、私たちが今行っている実験が
The past ten years collected by our farm
当農園が集めた過去10年間
Designed GIRL from all over Taiwan
台湾全土から集まったGIRLをデザイン
we are now working with them
私たちは今彼らと協力しています
Every year we also collect GIRL in the same place
毎年同じ場所でGIRLも集めています
we can see how fast it evolves
どれだけ早く進化するかがわかります
It can prove that the climate becomes warmer
気候が暖かくなっている証拠かもしれません
Will it affect the acceleration of the evolution of bacteria?
細菌の進化の加速に影響を与えるのでしょうか？
So I think I'll tell you the answer in 10 years
だから10年後に答えが分かると思う
The second time you are blooming and bearing fruit in the waterway
二度目の君は水路で花を咲かせ実を結ぶ
If you are too hot
暑すぎる場合
it turned out to be an empty bomb
それは空の爆弾だったことが判明した
It will affect the quality of its rice grain
米粒の品質に影響を及ぼします
Everyone, when you go to the market to buy
皆さん、市場に買いに行くときは、
This is what you should buy
これはあなたが買うべきものです
each one is transparent
それぞれが透明です
This is normal
これは正常です
It is a waterway with high nutritional value
栄養価の高い水路です
Have you seen many of these
これらをたくさん見たことがありますか
opaque we call them agronomists
不透明、私たちは彼らを農学者と呼びます
This is called a heart guard
これをハートガードといいます
This is from an empty bomb.
これは空の爆弾からのものです。
Then this is when you are blooming
それなら、これがあなたが咲いているときです
During the so-called development period you experience abnormal temperatures
いわゆる発育期には異常な気温が発生します
you will affect the outcome
あなたは結果に影響を与えるでしょう
So they have a system to determine that
彼らはそれを判断するシステムを持っています
The quality of rice grains
米粒の品質
Therefore, high temperature will also affect the quality of rice grains.
したがって、高温は米粒の品質にも影響を与えます。
another output
別の収量
The director of the aspect center of our middle school
私たちの中学校のアスペクトセンター長
Liu Shaocheng did a string experiment
劉少成は弦の実験を行った
Over the past few decades in Taiwan
過去数十年にわたり、私たちの台湾は
Our high temperature average
私たちの平均最高気温
Little change in Taiwan but one thing
台湾ではほとんど変化がありませんが、一つだけ
our evening
私たちの夜
temperature increase
気温の上昇
Ip Man's increase rate is much higher than other countries
イップ・マンの増加率は他国に比べてはるかに高い
The other is the temperature difference between day and night.
もう一つは昼夜の温度差です。
The temperature difference also becomes smaller
温度差も小さくなる
because it's hot at night
夜は暑いので
The words of plants play a role in the daytime
植物の言葉が昼間に活躍
At night, only respiration
夜は呼吸のみ
if your temperature is too high
体温が高すぎる場合
it breathes
それは呼吸する
In theory, it should be higher
理論的にはもっと高いはずです
This will affect its output
これは出力に影響します
International Rice Organization in the Philippines
フィリピンの国際米機関
they did the experiment
彼らは実験をしました
in their laboratory
彼らの研究室で
If you find that your average temperature at night has increased by one degree
夜の平均気温が1度上がったと感じたら
10% reduction in production
生産量10％削減
Taiwan over the past 100 years
過去100年の台湾
Our average leaf temperature is two degrees
私たちの葉の平均温度は2度です
Did you say it affected the output?
それが出力に影響を与えたと言いましたか？
There is no experimental proof
実験による証明はない
But I am from the Agricultural Department of National Taiwan University
しかし、私は国立台湾大学農学部の出身です。
The Times Received by Mr. Lu Sen
ルー・セン先生から受け取った時間
Only ours is 9599697
私たちのものだけが9599697です
We rice this is our project goal
私たちはこれが私たちのプロジェクトの目標です
This is our actual output
これは実際の出力です
You can see the goal of our project
私たちのプロジェクトのゴールが見えてきます
Much lower than our actual output
実際の生産高よりも大幅に低い
He estimated the goal of the plan
彼は計画の目標を見積もった
It means how much area we will plant this year
それは今年どれだけの面積を植えるかを意味します
So we expect that under normal conditions
したがって、通常の状況では次のようになると予想されます
how much output should he have
どれくらいの量のアウトプットが必要か
You see two consecutive years
2年連続で見られますね
In fact, his newer data keeps falling
実際、彼の新しいデータは減少し続けています
Is it affected by Ye Wen?
イェウェンの影響でしょうか？
Elevated leaf temperature affects rice yield
葉温の上昇は米の収量に影響を与える
Maybe but that's all we need to ask
おそらく、しかし私たちが尋ねなければならないのはそれだけです
So our concentrated environment in Taiwan
台湾における私たちの集中環境
Rice is not the only problem faced
直面している問題は米だけではない
Most concentrates face the same problem
ほとんどの濃縮物は同じ問題に直面しています
Because global warming will cause high temperature
地球温暖化で高温になるから
For example, its average temperature increases
たとえば、平均気温が上昇します。
Increased leaf temperature
葉温の上昇
The temperature difference decreases, and the other is the increase in extreme climate
寒暖差の減少、もう一つは異常気象の増加です。
It means that you have more days with strong wind and heavy rain
強風や大雨の日が増えるということです
So the plant was originally living in its original climate
つまり、植物は元々、元の気候の中で生きていたのです。
it has some adaptability
ある程度の適応力はある
It is now due to environmental changes
今は環境の変化により
Because the most important thing about Taiwan is that our terrain is very special
台湾について最も重要なことは、台湾の地形が非常に特殊であるということです。
So some changes are completely different from continental country changes
したがって、一部の変更は大陸国の変更とは完全に異なります
So we also hit the steel shore and we go along the water
それで私たちも鋼鉄の海岸にぶつかり、水に沿って進みます
There are other issues such as the use of oxygen temperature and water smoke
他にも酸素温度や水煙の利用などの問題もある
This is the standard that our crops face
これが私たちの作物が直面する基準です
What about you
あなたはどうですか
The first one I think is someone who does biotechnology
最初の人はバイオテクノロジーをやっている人だと思います
This is a very important question
これは非常に重要な質問です
In addition to the previous biotechnology industry, which is of course important
もちろん重要なこれまでのバイオテクノロジー産業に加えて、
and that we can definitely do
そして私たちには必ずできること
For example, that we already know how to do
たとえば、私たちはすでにやり方を知っている
This is certainly worth pursuing
これは確かに追求する価値があります
Are we facing this problem
私たちはこの問題に直面していますか
I think our government is probably starting to think
私たちの政府はおそらく考え始めていると思います
that's them
それが彼らです
The year 2010 is the main direction of the agricultural science and technology forward-looking issue that was set last year.
2010年は、昨年設定された農業科学技術の将来展望課題の主要な方向性である。
You can see that I listed a few that are now out.
現在公開されているもののいくつかをリストしたことがわかります。
It's on their government radar
それは政府のレーダーに載っています
This is why agricultural biotechnology also needs to face these problems
だからこそ、農業バイオテクノロジーもこうした問題に直面する必要があるのです。
This CCTV safety food safety
このCCTVの安全性食品の安全性
This promotion of the farmer's beard probably means
この農民のひげの宣伝は、おそらく次のことを意味します。
It's not just scientists
科学者だけではない
This should be the whole
これが全体であるはずです
That is to say, no matter what the social humanities and economics
つまり、社会人文科学や経済学に関係なく、
And this job, I think everyone should come in.
そしてこの仕事は、誰もが参加すべきだと思います。
and these few
そしてこれらのいくつかの
And this so-called sustainable utilization of production resources
そして、このいわゆる生産資源の持続可能な利用
As far as we're concerned, you do what you can
私たちに関する限り、あなたはできる限りのことをしてください
Because you seem to be talking about problems now, do you have any countermeasures?
今、問題点をおっしゃっているようですが、何か対策はありますか？
Then I think the first one is you, because the research we have been doing is actually very simple
それでは、最初の人はあなただと思います、なぜなら私たちが行ってきた研究は実際には非常に単純だからです
In fact, I am working along the water
実は私も水辺で仕事をしています
So what we do is very simple, what to do when you lack oxygen
それで、私たちがやることはとてもシンプルです、酸素が不足したときにどうするかです。
But now the plants in this field face not only flooding
しかし今、この畑の植物は洪水だけでなく、
It is faced because usually Taiwan flooding is down
普段は台湾の洪水が治まってるから直面する
So it usually faces high temperature and lack of oxygen
そのため、通常は高温と酸素不足に直面します
Few people do this, and most people do experiments in the laboratory at a temperature of more than 20 degrees.
これを行う人はほとんどおらず、ほとんどの人は 20 度を超える温度の実験室で実験を行います。
So the results of the experiment we did, if you want to go to the field to do it, probably most of it won't be needed
つまり、私たちが行った実験の結果は、実際に現場に行って実験したいのであれば、おそらくそのほとんどは必要ないでしょう。
So those of us who do basic research have to come back and ask questions in different ways
したがって、基礎研究を行う私たちは、戻ってきてさまざまな方法で質問する必要があります
That is to say, if you see the environment changes now, then you know the problems you may face
つまり、今環境が変化しているのを見ると、直面する可能性のある問題がわかるということです。
we're going to find out
私たちはそれを知るつもりです
For example, can you train this to warm the predictions of the two lipid groups?
たとえば、これをトレーニングして 2 つの脂質グループの予測を正確にすることができますか?
Well, this should actually be a big challenge.
まあ、これは実際には大きな挑戦であるはずです。
Because you are not only afraid of the heat
怖いのは暑さだけじゃないから
Are you still afraid of the difference between its night temperature and day temperature?
夜の気温と日中の気温の違いがまだ怖いですか？
That's a problem we've never faced before.
それは私たちがこれまでに直面したことのない問題です。
Then there are ice insect moxa, Huang Zhiying, water, and sheep adjustment
次に、氷虫灸、黄志英、水、羊の調整です。
It seems that I haven't mentioned this all the time.
このことについてはずっと言及していなかったような気がします。
But it's actually a serious problem
でも実は深刻な問題なのです
water
水
We all complain that this industrial age uses up a lot of water
私たちは皆、この工業化時代は水を大量に消費すると不平を言います。
Taiwan's agricultural water use is also very serious
台湾の農業用水利用も深刻
they also use a lot of water
彼らはまた大量の水を使用します
Do you think water is needed?
水は必要だと思いますか？
You grow water so much that it actually lives well without water
水をたくさん育てているので、実は水がなくても生きていけるのです
Planting water is because you plant it in water because it has
水を植えるということは、水の中に植えるからです。
It can mean that you can grow weeds
雑草が生える可能性があるということです
and that one
そしてそれは
Canals can survive without water
水がなくても生きていける
It's just that it may not be very productive
ただそれはあまり生産的ではないかもしれない
So now at the Center for International Waterways Research in the Philippines
それで今はフィリピンの国際水路研究センターにいる
They're starting to breed a new generation of waterway seeds
彼らは新世代の水路の種を育種し始めている
is that you use what they call Dry Cartigation
それはドライカートと呼ばれるものを使用することです
It is to be planted in the sweat field
汗田に植えられる予定です
This is totally different from before
これは以前とはまったく違います
Because if you want to sweat, you can't make a difference
汗をかきたくても何も変わらないから
also use fools
バカも使う
So besides cultivation techniques, you
つまり、栽培技術に加えて、
you have a new breed
あなたは新しい品種を持っています
You can still grow well that way
このままでも十分成長できるよ
We in Taiwan, I think we should also go this way
台湾にいる私たちも、この道を歩むべきだと思います
Because for example, if we use water for your waterways
なぜなら、例えば、水路に水を使用する場合、
don't take that long
そんなに長くかからないでください
For example, you don't want two and a half months
たとえば、2 か月半は要らないとします。
If you only let it last a month
1ヶ月だけ続ければ
Then save the water for three minutes
その後、水を3分間保存します
see what happens
何が起こるか見てみましょう
I want to do research on this
これについて研究したいです
none of us are doing it yet
私たちの誰もまだやっていません
This needs to be done in the Tenriya
これは天リヤでやるべきだ
So these are the ones we should develop
したがって、これらは私たちが開発すべきものです
There is also the so-called resistance to adversity
いわゆる逆境に対する耐性もあります
So one of our current ideas is
そこで、私たちの現在のアイデアの 1 つは、
We are tantamount to using biotechnology
私たちはバイオテクノロジーを使用しているのと同じです
we are not relying on the original
私たちはオリジナルに依存していません
Because of these environmental factors caused by the current environmental changes
現在の環境変化によるこれらの環境要因により、
Some plants have never been touched
まったく触れられていない植物もあります
So you have these sources
これらのソースがあります
That is to say, you have to go to the wild to find wild species.
つまり、野生種を見つけるためには野生に行かなければならないということです
It may be difficult to resist
抵抗するのは難しいかもしれない
The best thing we should do now is to use this so-called biotechnology method
私たちが今すべき最善のことは、このいわゆるバイオテクノロジー手法を使用することです
to create to create these various strains
これらのさまざまな系統を作成する
Then we have an early warning
それから、早期警告があります
Early warning and monitoring system
早期警報および監視システム
For example, we can predict the next ten years
たとえば、今後 10 年を予測できます。
maybe not now
今はそうじゃないかもしれない
Maybe what will happen to our Taiwanese companies in the next few years
おそらく今後数年で台湾企業はどうなるでしょうか
We can generalize this kind of system that we have experienced
私たちが経験したこの種のシステムを一般化することができます
This is of course in the planning stage.
もちろんこれは計画段階です。
but we already have teams that want to start doing their own thing
しかし、独自のことを始めたいと考えているチームはすでにあります
So I think this should be what I'm going to explain today.
したがって、これが今日私が説明する内容であるべきだと思います。
I think the role of the Academia Sinica in the field of agricultural biotechnology
農業バイオテクノロジーの分野における中央研究院の役割は次のとおりだと思います。
I think we have quite a few really good research energy
私たちは非常に優れた研究エネルギーをかなり持っていると思います
Also has various expertise
さまざまな専門知識も備えています
See the main direction of these our forward-looking topics right ahead of us
これらの将来を見据えたトピックの主な方向性を目の前で確認してください
I think our Academia Sinica should have at least these aspects
私たちの中央研究院には少なくともこれらの側面があるべきだと思います
we all have strengths
私たち全員が強みを持っています
In fact, we have been doing it since last year.
実は昨年からやっています。
Let's say it combines the Agricultural College of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学農学部を合わせたものとしましょう。
There is also our Agricultural Center and we have a teacher in the post office
農業センターもあり、郵便局には先生がいます
Then another economics student
それから別の経済学部の学生
We set up a big research team
私たちは大規模な研究チームを設立しました
Just to do what I said earlier
先ほど言ったことを実行するだけです
there is
がある
This is the goal of our research
これが私たちの研究の目標です
We also recently communicated with the International Water University Research Center
私たちは最近、国際水大学研究センターとも連絡を取りました。
Signed one is Number 2, etc.
署名されたものは番号 2 などです。
By our COA students
COA学生による
come to do research team
研究チームをやりに来てください
We are also research team
私たちも研究チームです
Signed one is Number 2, etc.
署名されたものは番号 2 などです。
by our Council of Agriculture
私たちの農業評議会による
That is to say, put some sutras
つまりお経を入れます。
IWU Research Center
国際水大学研究センター
Then our scientists in Taiwan
それから台湾の科学者たちが
You can go over there to do experiments
あそこに行って実験してもいいよ
means we get there
そこに到着することを意味します
you can use this money
このお金を使ってもいいよ
separated from the scientists there
そこの科学者たちとは別れた
Then this is actually a
それから、これは実際には
that is not easy
それは簡単ではありません
That is to say, it is actually quite an important achievement.
つまり、実はかなり重要な成果なのです。
Because the research center of the International Water University
国際水大学の研究センターなので
an organization under the United Nations
国連の下にある組織
that said earlier
それは前に言った
The previous president, the previous president was
前の社長、前の社長は
He doesn't dare to formally communicate with Taiwan whatever the Chinese mainland says.
中国本土が何と言おうと、彼は台湾と正式に意思疎通する勇気はない。
A German was changed as president last year
昨年ドイツ人が大統領に変わった
Then you are willing to formally sign NHR with us
その後、当社と正式に NHR に署名する意思がありますか
So our scientists in Taiwan can start now
台湾の科学者たちは今すぐ始められる
That is not only we have a team
それは私たちにチームがあるだけではありません
There is a formal cooperation contract
正式な協力契約がある
They also see that Academia Sinica has resources
彼らはまた、中央研究院がリソースを持っていることも理解しています。
So they are also willing to cooperate
だから彼らも喜んで協力してくれる
We hope that at least in the next five or ten years
少なくとも今後 5 年か 10 年以内にはそうなることを願っています。
We can contribute in addition to the Academia Sinica in the biotechnology industry
中央研究院以外にもバイオテクノロジー産業に貢献できる
We prefer to face the
私たちは直面することを好みます
the problems he faced in agriculture
彼が農業で直面した問題
Because it's actually a really big challenge
それは実際には本当に大きな挑戦だから
We hope we can have some contribution
少しでも貢献できれば幸いです
then i think i'll stop here today
それでは今日はここでやめておこうと思います
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you Mayor for your wonderful speech
市長、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
We have some time to open up your questions
ご質問をお受けする時間がございますので、
Do you want to ask him for advice?
彼にアドバイスを求めたいですか?
Mayor
市主任
I listen to talk and I have an association
話を聞いて連想する
We will also talk about the excavation of health food later.
健康食品の発掘についても後ほどお話します。
Taiwan now our civilian clothes
台湾は今私たちの私服です
Many peasant children including me
私を含む多くの農民の子供たちは
Don't eat rice that isn't farmed
栽培されていないお米は食べてはいけません
Afraid of fat
脂肪が怖い
so many of us now
今、私たちの多くが
don't eat rice at all
ご飯を全く食べない
So our colorectal cancer
つまり、私たちの大腸がんは
Already senior for three years
すでに3年目のシニアです
Are we the technology method you mentioned just now?
今おっしゃったテクノロジー方式でしょうか。
can put this rice
このご飯を入れてもいいですか
Our electric paper
当社の電子ペーパー
that saccharification
その糖化
Carbohydrate or reduce
炭水化物を摂取するか減らす
that keeps it nourished
それが栄養を保つ
Like what you said just now, people will be able to promote that
あなたが今言ったように、人々はそれを促進することができるでしょう
buy them extra high
特別に高く買う
Then encourage people to eat rice
そして人々に米を食べるよう奨励する
You can also check this
こちらもチェックできます
Dachanghai
大長海
The proportion of Dachanghai is a little bit higher
大長海の割合が少し高い
The average amount of rice our people eat is
私たちの人々が食べる米の平均量は、
It just happens to be more successful than
たまたまそれよりも成功しているだけです
fall again every year
毎年また落ちる
Dachanghai is increased every year
大長海は毎年増加しています
is this possible
これは可能ですか
this i think
これは私が思う
In theory it should be possible
理論的には可能なはずだ
but i think
しかし、私は思います
This Taiwan eats rice
この台湾はご飯を食べる
reduce i think
減らすと思います
not only because
という理由だけではありません
is the relationship between rice
お米の関係です
but
しかし
That is because you are economical
それはあなたが経済的だからです
Development now means diversification
発展とは今や多様化を意味する
That
それか
I'm different
私は別だ
Xianghua
香華
because
なぜなら
us
私たち
the reason why m said
Mがこう言う理由
Also in Taiwan
台湾でも
that can't mean
それは意味がありません
we start over
私たちはやり直します
eat
食べる
means you come back
あなたが戻ってくることを意味します
It is still enough for us to maintain the amount of rice we used to eat
今まで食べていたお米の量を維持するのに十分です
that's where we put you
そこが私たちがあなたを置く場所です
The use of rice makes it diversified
お米を使うことで多様化する
Then why can English be used as fodder?
ではなぜ英語が餌になるのでしょうか？
Why can't this text be used as fodder?
なぜこのテキストをネタとして使ってはいけないのでしょうか？
So now the Council of Agriculture also has
そこで現在、農業評議会も
they don't like to use the word
彼らはその言葉を使うのが好きではない
That is to say, to develop another batch of
つまり、別のバッチを開発するには、
Don't spend so much effort planting
植えるのにそれほど労力を費やさないでください
That rice can be used as fodder
その米は飼料として利用できる
Taiwan imports a lot every year
台湾は毎年大量に輸入している
Encourage it to be used as feed
飼料として利用するよう奨励する
so this is
それでこれは
Maybe doesn't directly answer your question
もしかしたらあなたの質問に直接答えていないかもしれません
You said you want to change the rice
ご飯おかわりしたいって言ってたよね
i think probably
おそらくだと思います
if someone does
誰かがそうしたら
should be fine
大丈夫なはずです
but I use another way
でも私は別の方法を使っています
I think you can use it in other ways
他の使い方もできると思います
Because we spent a lot of foreign exchange
多額の外貨を使ったので
importing this carrier
このキャリアを輸入しています
And most people make feed outside
そしてほとんどの人は屋外で餌を作ります
Now the Council of Agriculture has finally remembered
今、農業委員会はついに思い出した
So do they want someone now?
それで、彼らは今誰かが欲しいのですか？
Hearing this word, this is called feed rice
この言葉を聞くと、これを飼料米と言います
They eat with people because of this, they want to share the fun
彼らは人々と一緒に食事をするので、楽しみを共有したいと考えています
OK, thank you
わかりました、ありがとう
I would like to ask the host that
主催者に聞きたいのですが、
Food is a global problem
食糧は世界的な問題です
I always wanted to start with that green biotech
私はいつもそのグリーンバイオテクノロジーから始めたいと思っていました
I want to ask if there is such a concept
そういう概念があるのか​​聞きたい
The one that uses the animal to join its photosynthesis
動物を光合成に利用するもの
that possibility
その可能性
animals directly form photosynthesis
動物は直接光合成を行う
like this
このような
I think it might be a bit difficult
ちょっと難しいかも知れませんが
Because it photosynthesizes it has
光合成をするので、
In fact, the source of its gene is two sets
実はその遺伝子の源は2セットある
A set is from real and biological
セットは実際の生物からのものです
The other set is the continuation of the photosynthesis
もう一組は光合成の続きです
so you just say
だからあなたはただ言うだけです
This should be counted as the fainting of animals and plants.
これは動植物の失神として数えるべきである。
It should be a billion
10億になるはずだよ
so i think you have to be in
だからあなたも参加する必要があると思います
It's kind of hard to change the consequences of this evolution right now
この進化の結果を今変えるのはちょっと難しい
but you never say
でもあなたは決して言わない
That means we have glow fish, glow pigs
つまり、光る魚や光る豚がいるということです
Are we talking about the possibility of this direction
この方向性の可能性について話しているのでしょうか
Fluorescent fish is actually very simple
蛍光魚って実はとてもシンプルなんです
it's just a gene
それはただの遺伝子です
fluorescent protein
蛍光タンパク質
that is very simple
それはとても簡単です
Your role of light is the whole package
あなたの光の役割はパッケージ全体です
That's the white gene
それが白人の遺伝子です
that might be a bit difficult
それは少し難しいかもしれません
But this scientific progress
しかし、この科学の進歩は、
I will give an example
例を挙げます
When we used to do DNA sequencing
DNA 配列決定を行っていたとき
in my time
私の時代には
If you set a preface, it will be a very good PayPal
前置きをするととてもお得なPayPalになります
Some people graduate with an order
命令で卒業する人もいる
When doing the sequencing of the human genome
ヒトゲノムの解読を行うとき
the god with a golden frog
金のカエルを持つ神
is the discovery of the great Boiri
偉大なボイリの発見です
He said why do you want to make this order?
彼は、なぜこの順序を設定したいのですかと言いました。
He said that this sequencing technology
彼は、このシーケンス技術は、
even a monkey can do it
猿でもできる
At that time, it has progressed to only 20 years
当時はまだ20年しか経っていない
Then if you compare now with that of 20 years ago
では、20年前と今を比べてみると
About 1000 times better
約1000倍良い
So that technique has bad speed
だからそのテクニックはスピードが悪い
Probably not at least 1000 times
おそらく少なくとも1000回ではないでしょう
It may be ten thousand times more
1万倍かもしれない
So I will say No to your question
したがって、あなたの質問にはノーと答えます
但You never know
でもあなたには決して分からない
OK
OK
thank you for his speech today
今日の彼のスピーチに感謝します
What I would like to ask is
私が聞きたいのは、
It was mentioned at the beginning
冒頭でも触れましたが
Swiss scientist would love to share his name
スイスの科学者は自分の名前を共有したいと考えている
But there are some companies that he has patents and refuses to
しかし、彼が特許を取得しているにもかかわらず、特許を取得することを拒否している企業もいくつかあります。
It is also mentioned that Monsanto has many
モンサント社が多くの企業を持っていることも述べられました。
These related patents
これらの関連特許
But just now it was said that the international bandit democrats
しかし今、国際的な盗賊民主主義者たちが言った。
He'd love to open up all his bandit comments
彼は盗賊のコメントをすべて公開したいと考えています
I feel like the attitude is completely different
態度が全然違う気がする
I also heard that there is a kind of service patent in the United States.
アメリカにはサービス特許のようなものがあるとも聞きました。
Does that mean Taiwan is in this entire future crisis?
この将来の危機全体が台湾なのでしょうか？
Shouldn't this be the way to protect yourself?
これが自分を守る方法ではないでしょうか？
Or it should not be completely open.
言い換えれば、完全に開いてはいけません。
There is one thing about this, you are beyond my ability, but I can tell you that when the ordering began in the early days, many individuals or companies patented their series, and they were all approved at that time.
これについては 1 つあります。あなたには私の能力を超えていますが、初期に注文が始まったとき、多くの個人または企業がそのシリーズの特許を取得し、その時点ですべて承認されたと言えます。
But now you only need to challenge the invalidation of those patents, because now it is what you want, you only have to sequence, that is just an information, this is useless,
しかし、今では、それらの特許の無効化に異議を申し立てるだけで済みます。なぜなら、それがあなたが望むものだからです。あなたは配列するだけで十分です。それは単なる情報であり、これは役に立ちません。
I think at least in our Taiwan, that is to say, the International Rice Organization, it made it, it was pre-planted, because it is an international organization, so it does not need that,
少なくとも私たちの台湾、つまり国際米機関では、それが作られ、事前に植え付けられたと思います。なぜなら、それは国際機関だから、その必要はありません。
And it didn't use it, it didn't use the so-called fonts, that is, patented ones, but I think we need to develop in Taiwan, of course we need patents,
いわゆるフォント、つまり特許取得済みのフォントは使用していませんでしたが、台湾で開発する必要があると思います、もちろん特許が必要です、
But it is used to protect ourselves, the example of Mr. Hong is very good, and our central government is also very patented, but we can be endless, that is, we don’t reward those who need tools. I think this is what we need.
しかし、それは自分たちを守るために使われています。ホン氏の例はとても良いです。私たちの中央政府も特許をたくさん取得していますが、私たちは無限に行くことができます。つまり、ツールを必要とする人たちに報酬を与えることはありません。私たちは私たちだと思います」これが必要です。
I must collect his money
彼のお金を集めなければなりません
Because Jin Ming is courageous, Jin Ming belongs to Mengshan
ジンミンは勇気があるので、ジンミンは蒙山に属します
The one with the most rice gene patents is also Mengshan's
イネの遺伝子特許を最も多く取得しているのも蒙山社である。
So one day we must challenge his patents
したがって、いつか私たちは彼の特許のいくつかに異議を唱えなければなりません
Because he is only sequenced
彼はただ順番に並べられているだけだから
I think this Faguo company has its own commercial considerations
このFaguo社には独自の商業上の考慮事項があると思います
But I guess we're scientists
でも私たちは科学者だと思います
It's you, you have to take the exam yourself
それはあなたです、あなたは自分で試験を受けなければなりません
But our country's industrial view
しかし、我が国の産業観は
Or the point of view that you will solve the problem in the future
または将来的に問題を解決するという観点
i think i have to protect myself
自分を守らなければいけないと思う
sorry
ごめん
But teacher, you just said that
でも先生、さっきそう言ったんですよ
If Meng Shandu develops faster
孟善ドゥの成長が早ければ
he got the patent
彼は特許を取得した
Then we can't develop any more.
それでは、これ以上発展することはできません。
Mengshantou's products are not the same
蒙山頭の製品は同じではありません
He invented it himself
彼はそれを自分で発明した
he sold it
彼はそれを売った
His RUNUP was not invented by him
彼のRUNUPは彼が発明したものではありません
He studied from one university to another in New Jersey
彼はニュージャージー州のある大学から別の大学へ学んだ
Buy him from that person
あの人から彼を買ってください
Tell him to buy SPRS
SPRSを買うように彼に伝えてください
It's not his picture, their own research and development is not so powerful
それは彼の写真ではありません、彼ら自身の研究開発はそれほど強力ではありません
Because you are him in March
だってあなたは三月の彼だから
Because I personally do basic research
個人的に基礎研究をしているので
If you do a research, you set a goal at the beginning
研究するなら最初に目標を設定する
I must solve this problem
この問題を解決しなければなりません
often only ten to eighty nine you will not succeed
多くの場合、10 から 89 まででは成功しないでしょう
You can click, thank you teacher
クリックしていただけます、先生ありがとう
It's okay, teacher, I should be old enough
大丈夫です、先生、私ももう十分な年齢ですよ
i think because i am a middle school teacher
中学校の先生だからそう思う
Then every time I come to listen to the middle school speech
それから中学校の演説を聞きに来るたびに
I think they will bring a lot of things back to the students in our school
彼らは私たちの学校の生徒たちに多くのものをもたらしてくれると思います
It's like in the future high school curriculum
まるで未来の高校のカリキュラムのようだ
biotechnology, there is an applied biotechnology is to explore
バイオテクノロジーには応用バイオテクノロジーがあり、それを探求する必要があります
Give the teacher some examples of what you mentioned today
先生に今日話した内容の例をいくつか挙げてください
So I am very happy to come here to take classes
だからここに来て授業を受けることができてとてもうれしいです
You can bring many examples back to share
多くの例を持ち帰って共有できます
I'll take a look now
今から見てみます
Please go back and share more examples
戻って他の例を共有してください
In the past few years, I have actually listened to many courses on plant essence transplantation.
ここ数年、私は実際に植物エッセンス移植に関する多くの講座を聞いてきました。
course for teachers
教師向けコース
So one thing I want to ask is
それで一つお聞きしたいのですが、
Teacher, what you mentioned at the beginning is
先生、冒頭でおっしゃったのは、
In the domestic part in Taiwan
台湾国内部分では
In principle, we are not allowed to
原則としてお断りさせていただいております
Changed some crops
一部の作物を変更しました
Whether it's rice
お米かどうか
Or what I heard at National Taiwan University
あるいは国立台湾大学で聞いたこと
Sweet potato is also good
スイートポテトもいいですね
Or the tomato you just mentioned
あるいは、あなたが今言ったトマト
The application of stone mustard
ストーンマスタードの塗布
It's like what the teacher just said
先生が今おっしゃった通りです
You want to address a lot of rice productivity decline
米の生産性の大幅な低下に対処したい
issues related to climate change
気候変動に関連した問題
In the future, if you really
将来、もし本当にそうなら、
when something like this is produced
このようなものが生成されると
Isn't it going to be used in Taiwan?
台湾では使われないのですか？
Then you are the first policy and you will get stuck
そうなると、あなたが最初の政策になってしまい、行き詰まってしまいます。
the second one i think
2番目は私が思う
It just so happens that the deputy dean is also here.
たまたま副学部長もここにいらっしゃいます。
I don't know you
私はあなたを知りません
it's you officers
それはあなたたち役員です
Is there a way to provide some input
何らかの入力を提供する方法はありますか
How can I convince students in the future
今後どうやって生徒を説得すればいいのか
especially interested in biotechnology
特にバイオテクノロジーに興味がある
Students who want to engage in precision transplantation and application
精密移植・応用に取り組みたい学生
I won't go in after this one
この後は入りません
It's great when it's done and it comes out for one thing
何かを成し遂げたときは素晴らしいことだ
I also want to help Taiwanese
私も台湾人を助けたい
But I'm not in Taiwan
でも台湾にはいないよ
room for development
開発の余地
Here are the two questions I want to ask
ここで私が聞きたいのは2つの質問です
Thanks
ありがとう
ok the first question is not
OK、最初の質問は違います
i think it should be soon
すぐにすべきだと思う
Our Council of Agriculture has already contacted the Department of Health
私たちの農業評議会はすでに保健省に連絡済みです
have already formulated these
すでにこれらを策定している
That is to say, genetically modified crops are pre-tests
つまり、遺伝子組み換え作物は事前試験です
and safety assessments and food safety assessments
安全性評価と食品安全性評価
This policy is all here
このポリシーのすべてがここにあります
The next stage is to say
次の段階で言うと、
Do you want quasi-GM crops to go on the market?
準遺伝子組み換え作物を市場に出したいですか?
I want to say that after all these years of discussion
私が言いたいのは、何年もの議論を経て、
my prediction is
私の予想は
In the beginning, it was likely that the main Taiwanese
当初は台湾人がメインだったと思われます。
I don't think the water is right
水が合わないと思う
But the others, especially the Fahui
しかし他の人々、特に法会は
It should be right, just like a fluorescent fish
それは正しいはず 蛍光魚のように
So I think the main thing is
それで、私が思うに重要なことは、
This is not just a Taiwan problem
これは台湾だけの問題ではない
In Europe, genetically modified crops are not allowed to be
ヨーロッパでは遺伝子組み換え作物は一切認められていない
So let the Americans rule the world
だからアメリカ人に世界を支配させましょう
that this but you too I guess it's a comparison
これはあなたもだけど、それは比較だと思う
This is tantamount to being a member of politics and society
それは政治や社会の一員であることに等しい
Then I'm not that desperate
それなら私はそこまで絶望的ではない
i think it should
そうすべきだと思います
That is to say, you, especially I think we scientists also have a part of our responsibility
つまり、あなた、特に私たち科学者にも責任の一端があると思います
Because when we go out to talk to that, that is to say, society, this is
なぜなら、私たちが社会、つまり社会と話しに行くとき、これは
The one who is equal to the dialogue is not so enthusiastic
会話に対等な人はそれほど熱心ではない
I think this is you Taiwan is a democratic country
これはあなただと思います 台湾は民主主義です
You want a policy, this is actually a pretty big policy
あなたは政策が必要ですが、これは実際にはかなり大きな政策です
I think you should just say
ただ言ったほうがいいと思います
Although I know I know it's a good thing
それが良いことだとわかっていても
But you still have to be able to convince the society
しかし、それでも社会を説得できなければなりません
Most of the general public will accept you as this
一般大衆のほとんどはあなたをこのように受け入れるでしょう
Then I think Taiwan can be smart
そうすれば台湾は賢くなれると思う
I think you have a conversation that should work out
うまくいくはずの会話があると思います
And our government should say they
そして私たちの政府はこう言うべきです
At least two years ago the attitude started
少なくとも2年前からそのような態度が始まった
I was talking about that at the beginning
冒頭でもそんな話してたけど
the constitutional one
憲法上のもの
The chairman of the Council of Agriculture and the chairman of the vice-chairman Cai Bing will not
農業評議会議長と副議長の蔡炳氏は辞任しない。
now that is to say
つまり今は
Because their considerations are not scientific objections at all.
なぜなら、彼らの考察はまったく科学的な反論ではないからです。
but political considerations
しかし、政治的配慮
I think this can be resolved through dialogue.
話し合いで解決できると思います。
should come
来る必要があります
I think most of the regulations are already in the Executive Yuan
ほとんどの規制はすでに行政院にあると思います
So wait for another discussion now
それでは、別の議論を待ちます
Then maybe in a few years
それから数年後かもしれない
At least we all have these quizzes
少なくとも私たちは皆、これらのクイズを持っています
Then there are laws
それから法律もあります
So I guess if there's interest I guess it should
だから興味があるならそうすべきだと思う
at least become a scientist
少なくとも科学者になってください
It is a very important report field
非常に重要なレポート分野です
I think this and the others are probably
これと他のものはおそらくそうだと思います
It's the newsroom of the guardian
ガーディアンのニュースルームです
Thank you, thank you Mayor for your wonderful speech
ありがとう、市長、素晴らしいスピーチをしてくれてありがとう
My personal question is related to the previous question
私の個人的な質問は前の質問に関連しています
Then the mayor mentioned in the report that
すると市長は報告書の中で次のように述べました。
This is the development of biotechnology
これがバイオテクノロジーの発展です
One thing that needs to be considered is the impact on the ecology
考慮する必要があるのは生態系への影響です。
We know that in Europe and America
ヨーロッパやアメリカではそれがわかっています
It has a very important role in the development of biotechnology
バイオテクノロジーの発展において非常に重要な役割を果たしています
That is to say, to engage in the so-called Tianjian experiment
つまり、いわゆる天津実験に従事することです。
Inmimental Release
インミメンタルリリース
Because in this biomodified crop
なぜなら、この生物組み換え作物では
Before licensing
ライセンス取得前
So I don't know that in our country
だから私の国では何と言えばいいのか分からない
If you are engaged in the development of biotechnology
バイオテクノロジーの開発に携わっている方
Is it necessary to engage in the so-called big sky experiment?
いわゆる大空実験を行う必要があるのでしょうか？
this is my problem thanks
これは私の問題です、ありがとう
we have this rule
私たちにはこのルールがあります
Taiwan now has two
台湾には現在2つあります
Actually there are several stages
実際にはいくつかの段階があります
One is your small field experiment
1 つは小規模な野外実験です
Now the South Center of Academia Sinica, Chung Hsing University
現在は中興大学中央研究南センター
There are also farms with this facility
この施設を備えた農園もあります
That means you can do small-scale facilities for genetically modified crops
つまり、遺伝子組み換え作物のための小規模な施設を建設できるということです。
Then the large scale you mentioned is only owned by the Central University and the Farming Department.
そうしますと、あなたがおっしゃった大規模なものは中央大学と農業部だけが所有しているものでございます。
Now that's the papaya I was talking about
それが私が話していたパパイヤです
Teacher Ye Xidong's papaya is already doing experiments at this stage
Ye Xidong先生のパパイヤはこの段階ですでに実験を行っています
Mr. Chen Nongwang's frog dishes are still being made on a small scale
陳農旺さんのカエル料理は今も小規模で作られている
windy
風が強い
so yes we have
はい、あります
It is only because the regulations for genetically modified crops to be marketed have really matured in the past two years
それはひとえに、遺伝子組み換え作物を販売するための規制が過去 2 年間で完全に成熟したからです。
Now it’s still called the Chief, and it’s still called the Draft in the Executive Yuan.
今でもそれは長官と呼ばれており、行政院では依然として草案と呼ばれています。
but he already said
しかし彼はすでに言いました
Because you have farmers though the market for papaya is mainly in India
パパイヤの市場は主にインドですが、農家がいるからです。
India still has to see you in Taiwan before he accepts it
インドは受け入れる前に台湾であなたに会わなければなりません
So our Council of Agriculture has taken this into consideration
したがって、私たちの農業評議会はこれを考慮しました
So now there is a set here
さて、ここにセットがあります
So that instruction you said
それで、あなたが言ったその指示は
This problem also exists for other machine modification linkages.
この問題は、他のマシン変更リンクにも存在します。
there is a problem here
ここに問題があります
Now in the market I see
今市場に出回っているのがわかります
I see in the market later
後で市場で見ます
In short, it will become less and less
要するに、どんどん少なくなっていきます
Just one of the models before
以前のモデルの 1 つだけ
Modified machine
改造機
So in terms of biodiversity
生物多様性の観点から言えば
from this icon
このアイコンから
The second question is that you need to say
2 番目の質問は、次のように言う必要があります。
Mention does not have to
言及する必要はない
to be in the model
モデルになること
They are all in the machine, mainly for themselves
それらはすべてマシンの中にあり、主に自分自身のためにあります
reduced one re-open
再オープンを 1 回削減
Then you mentioned that yes
それからあなたはそうだと言いました
you mentioned again
あなたはまた言いました
If it is said to be a successful usage in this press
この報道で成功した使い方と言われれば
just use that
それを使ってください
Why can't we use our current adoption method
なぜ現在の導入方法が使えないのか
exist
存在
super far one that is pressed
押された超遠いもの
say the method used
当該方法
Then use the method
次に、メソッドを使用します
or a poker
またはポーカー
can be in that kind of
そのような状態になることができます
at this
この時点で
in sweep usage
スイープ使用時
Second, if we talk about those few things, what are they?
第二に、それらのいくつかのことについて話すとしたら、それは何でしょうか?
OK that
わかりました
The first question is whether it will affect biodiversity
最初の質問は生物多様性に影響を与えるかどうかです
because
なぜなら
all
全て
Because of the GMOs you made
あなたが作ったGMOのせいで
probably have a market
おそらく市場があるでしょう
so you should be all
だからあなたも全員であるべきです
so-called making
いわゆる作り物
In fact, the object itself is a
実際、オブジェクト自体は
one
一個
This is what you plant in a unit area
単位面積内に植えるものです
So I don't think it should affect the so-called
したがって、いわゆるものに影響を与えるべきではないと思います
biodiversity
生物多様性
Our diversity is actually
私たちの多様性は実は
it's not us
それは私たちではありません
There's no variety, you're just one of those kinds
多様性なんてない、あなたもその中の一人に過ぎない
So I guess it shouldn't be a big problem
なので大きな問題にはならないと思います
As for that
それに関しては
I think it means why are you so watery?
どうしてそんなに水っぽいの？という意味だと思います。
Just don't use water, why not use that cauliflower
水は使わないで、カリフラワーを使えばいいのでは？
I think it's cost related
コストの関係だと思う
It is how much labor you need to spend, how much you can plant
どれだけの労力を費やす必要があるか、どれだけの量を植えることができるかを意味します。
Like the way of American Chinese artists
アメリカの中国人アーティストのやり方のように
He is completely mechanical, he is very dense
彼は完全に機械的で、非常に緻密です
So the species he encountered was
そこで彼が出会った種は、
That is, he can only go up, but not bend
つまり、彼は上がるこ​​としかできませんが、曲がることはできません
So what kind of disaster do you want?
それで、あなたはどんな災害を望んでいますか？
what kind do you want
どのようなものが欲しいですか
i want this
これ欲しい
What we call a crop, his competitive
私たちが作物と呼ぶもの、彼の競争力
Actually not very big
実際にはそれほど大きくありません
So when you get water, you use water to help him
だから、水が手に入るときは、水を使って彼を助けるのです
let him grow up well
彼を元気に育ててください
he's used to it
彼はそれに慣れている
That is to say, in fact, we humans have been planting water for almost 10,000 years.
つまり、実際には、私たち人間はほぼ1万年にわたって水を植えてきました。
So I guess the ones that are more popular now
だから今はそっちのほうが人気あると思うよ
Maybe I said it doesn't need water to live
生きるのに水は必要ないって言ったのかもしれない
just say it can live
それは生きられるとだけ言ってください
But its competitiveness is not necessarily so strong
しかし、その競争力は必ずしも強いわけではない
So I guess there is still a need for a new flat tide
つまり、新しいフラットタイドがまだ必要だと思います
As for the problems of miscellaneous tides
諸潮の問題についても
I think this is roughly
大体こんな感じだと思います
with the technical aspects of agriculture that we have now
私たちが現在持っている農業の技術的側面と
It should be possible to cultivate
栽培できるはずだ
So I have a final
だから決勝戦があるんだ
We want to be equal to our new technology
私たちは新しいテクノロジーと同等でありたいと考えています
plus that cultivation
それに加えてその栽培
Is it possible to have a set of platforms to do it?
それを行うための一連のプラットフォームを用意することは可能ですか?
I don't know if this answers your question
これがあなたの質問の答えになるかどうかわかりません
I want to ask the teacher
先生に聞きたいのですが
It's about reproductive energy.
生殖エネルギーについてです。
Teacher, we just mentioned today
先生、今日もお話しましたが
It's because there seem to be many more
他にもたくさんありそうなので
Technology to break down living things to do
生き物を分解する技術
What is the teacher
先生は何ですか
Do you think, for example, Higher Brand or MicroRG
たとえば、Higher Brand や MicroRG などだと思いますか?
Which one does the teacher think is more likely to be commercialized in the future?
先生はどちらが将来的に商品化される可能性が高いと思いますか？
Also, what research technologies must be done before commercialization
また、事業化するまでにどのような研究技術を行う必要があるか
Then we can do business
そうすればビジネスができる
I think the problem has two
問題には2つあると思います
The first question he asked was to say
彼が最初に尋ねた質問はこう言いました
Because we have a team of researchers, including Wang Wuyuan
なぜなら、私たちにはWang Wuyuanを含む研究者チームがいるからです。
We are doing reproductive agriculture in a pretty big team
私たちはかなり大きなチームで生殖農業を行っています
What we do in reproductive agriculture is the second generation
私たちが行う再生産農業は第二世代です
That is, we don't use electrograin to ferment, but to make alcohol
つまり、エレクトログレインを使用して発酵するのではなく、アルコールを製造するのです。
We use plant cell currency
植物細胞通貨を使用します
That is to say, some people say that plants can dance
つまり、植物は踊ることができるという人もいます。
To make it cell money, cell money is mainly cellulose and pie cellulose
セルマネーにするために、セルマネーは主にセルロースとパイセルロースです
Convert it to brassan for your flower effect
花の効果を得るためにブラッサンに変換します
I think this technique should work
このテクニックは効果があるはずだと思います
The other is the source of cell coins
もう1つはセルコインのソースです
If someone tells you that the agricultural association can let you use it as the main source of alcohol
農協がアルコールの主原料として使用させてくれると言ったら
You tell him to do the math
あなたは彼に計算するように言います
If you really want to use reproduction to make alcohol
本当に生殖を利用してアルコールを作りたい場合
you must have reproductive crops
生殖作物が必要です
talking crops
しゃべる作物
You can't just rely on agriculture and corporate affairs
農業と商事だけに頼ってはいけない
if you really want to replace
本当に交換したい場合は
For example, 230% of Petronas
たとえば、ペトロナスの 230%
You must be an eloquent crop
あなたは言葉の塊に違いない
You can't say that relying on agriculture will lead to business
農業に頼ればビジネスにつながるとは言えない
Then I also object to using Dao sense to make alcohol
それから、私はDaoセンスを使ってアルコールを作ることにも反対します
Because Taiwanese farmers have their own reasons for feeling burned.
なぜなら、台湾の農民には焼け付くような理由があるからだ。
because he returns nutrients to the land
栄養分を大地に還すから
He burned the second one
彼は二番目のものを燃やした
In fact, it can be said that the soil inside
実は、内部の土壌とも言えます。
Burnt from soft or something
ソフトか何かで焼けた
So although they are air pollution
ですから、大気汚染ではありますが、
There is air pollution
大気汚染がある
Then this is what you want to evaluate
じゃあ評価したいのはこれだ
But if you really put all your sense of Tao
でも本当にタオの感覚をすべて注ぎ込むなら
take it all
それをすべて取る
First, your cost is definitely not enough
まず、コストが明らかに十分ではありません
Because Taiwan is all small farmers
台湾は小規模農家ばかりなので
so you take the sense
だからあなたは意味を理解します
To gather together to do even nine thousand
9,000でもするために集まる
You don't have enough money for the first one
最初のものを買うにはお金が足りない
the second you will
次にあなたはそうします
Your nutrients did not return to that land
あなたの養分はあの地には戻らなかった
So your question I think is
それであなたの質問は次のように思います
you must have energy crops
エネルギー作物が必要です
Taiwan land in small
台湾の国土は狭い
Don't Make Your Own Energy Crops
エネルギー作物を自分で作らないでください
we develop technology
私たちは技術を開発します
After your technology matures,
テクノロジーが成熟した後、
see if you can do that
それができるかどうか見てください
but i think you really want alternative energy
でもあなたは本当に代替エネルギーを望んでいると思います
Early class I want variety
初期クラスは多様性が欲しい
you can't just rely on
ただ頼ることはできない
For example, if you only rely on a certain energy crop
たとえば、特定のエネルギー作物のみに依存している場合
Of course everyone is groping now
もちろん今はみんな手探り中です
The second generation of that even energy technology
その均一エネルギー技術の第二世代
so if you want
それで、もし望むなら
Taiwan will be like the people
台湾も国民のようになるだろう
have enough scientific energy
十分な科学的エネルギーがある
So we should develop more
だからもっと開発すべきだ
If you want to develop even without
無くても開発したいなら
do a few first
最初にいくつかやってみる
And take the road of technological development
そして技術開発の道を歩む
Then when the time comes, you actually have the key technology
そして時が来れば、実際に重要なテクノロジーを手に入れることができます
Research material is not
研究資料はそうではありません
That is, if other places can
つまり、他の場所でも可能であれば、
can want
望むことができる
you have technology
あなたには技術があります
Your research is definitely a problem
あなたの研究には間違いなく問題があります
So I think what we want to develop in Taiwan is the middle section
台湾で開発したいのはミドルセクションだと思います
technology
テクノロジー
next our children
次は私たちの子供たち
What about everyone?
みんなはどうですか？
Where
どこ
our disorder
私たちの障害
Plant a tree in ten years and turn it into a tree in a year
10年で木を植えて1年で木になる
If you think this tree can grow and be used in one year
この木が1年で成長して使えると思うなら
Then I think the development of existing energy is a very breakthrough
そうなると、既存のエネルギーの開発は非常に画期的だと思います
The second is that there was a newspaper report recently that
２つ目は、最近こんな新聞報道がありました。
Abroad is already researching something
海外ではすでに何かを研究している
called artificial leaves
人工葉と呼ばれる
It is said that only God can make leaves
葉っぱを作れるのは神だけだと言われています
But now people can already make leaves
しかし今では人々はすでに葉を作ることができます
Then this leaf is made
それからこの葉が作られます
It can accept light
光を受け入れることができる
Then it can be generated
そうすれば生成できる
even a mimic leaf
擬態葉さえも
When it passes through the American Department
アメリカ省を通過する場合
both sides of its leaves
葉の両面
One side is to divide water into green and oxygen
片方は水を緑と酸素に分ける
one side is green
片面は青です
one side is oxygen
片面は酸素です
In this way, the oxygen can be separated
このようにして酸素を分離することができます。
Then of course it can change
それならもちろん変わるかもしれない
So its ideal is to say
したがって、その理想は次のようになります。
Ordinary households can take advantage of this technology
一般家庭でも活用できる技術
workers to their own power
労働者は自らの力で
two topics
2つのトピック
One is a bit earlier
一つは少し早いです
time book report
タイムブックレポート
one is a newspaper report that came in
一つは入ってきた新聞報道です
Then these two questions
それでは、この 2 つの質問
I don't know what's inside our courtyard
うちの中庭に何があるのか​​分からない
Have you thought about it in this direction?
この方向で考えたことはありますか？
Thanks
ありがとう
I can answer the first question
最初の質問には答えられます
i think nature
自然だと思います
is there such a number
そんな数字あるの？
Number of developments
開発数
He grows several meters a year
彼は一年に数メートル成長します
so in
それで
Northern Europe and Australia
北欧とオーストラリア
They've put the number in order
彼らは番号を並べました
then they
それから彼らは
Also take this as an eloquent crop
これも雄弁な作物として捉えてください
There are also word making materials
単語作成素材もあります
so
それで
have we ever thought
私たちは考えたことがありますか
have
もつ
But we don't think about counting
しかし私たちは数を数えるということを考えません
we want basket flowers
私たちはかごの花が欲しいです
Because the basket flowers from that
そこからかごの花が咲くから
Get out of that organization
その組織から出て行け
I'm going to that seedling again
またあの苗のところへ行くよ
almost two years
ほぼ2年
Then why does he grow so fast
ではなぜ彼はそんなに早く成長するのでしょうか
so slow
とても遅いです
then we use this
それからこれを使います
basic science perspective
基礎科学の視点
come and see this
これを見に来てください
but
しかし
Some blue parks in the south are interested in hearing us do this
南部のいくつかの青い公園は私たちの取り組みに興味を持っています
They said whether to cooperate with the industry association
彼らは業界団体と協力するかどうかを言った
This is still far from cooperation
これはまだ協力には程遠い
All we have to ask is why butterfly blue
私たちが尋ねなければならないのは、なぜ蝶が青いのかということだけです
the rate at which its cells divide
その細胞が分裂する速度
That is to say it grows so slowly
つまり成長がとても遅いということです
why two years
なぜ2年なのか
Because some varieties of blue flowers do not need a year
青い花の品種によっては一年を必要としないものもありますので、
It can be from planting flower buds to fruiting
花芽から実まで成長することができます
so we are thinking
それで私たちは考えています
but we are thinking
しかし私たちは考えています
In fact, if you say that you are not affected by the industry, you are lying.
実際、業界の影響を受けていないと言ったら嘘になります。
because we people ask us
なぜなら私たち人々は私たちに尋ねるからです
that is, can you do this
つまり、これができますか
so we start thinking
それで私たちは考え始めます
so we're thinking
それで私たちは考えています
This is actually a very difficult problem
これは実はとても難しい問題です
Because this question is for people who are doing plants
植物をやっている方への質問ですので
This question is rarely asked
この質問はめったに聞かれません
That is to say, your cells divide in the plant body
つまり、植物の体内で細胞が分裂します。
how to be controlled
どのようにコントロールされるのか
and the growth of its cells
そしてその細胞の成長
Cell Size Control
セルサイズの制御
this is rarely done
これはめったに行われません
so we are thinking
それで私たちは考えています
naturally
当然
And there is this diversity
そして、この多様性があります
So this is an interesting success problem
これは興味深い成功問題です
this i think will do
これでいいと思います
it is possible and someone is thinking
それは可能だし、誰かが考えている
The second question is to compare
2番目の質問は比較することです
Also a bit out of my field
こちらも少し専門外ですが
because i know someone who was
だった人を知っているので
Because of this light ear effect
この光耳効果のせいで
You said that this leaf should have oxygen and water
この葉っぱには酸素と水があるはずだと君は言った
that actually
それは実際に
The process itself is not so simple
プロセス自体はそれほど単純ではありません
there is that
それはあります
have nobel prize winners
ノーベル賞受賞者がいる
just do that
ただそれをしてください
The electronic group component of the karmic body
カルマ体の電子グループの構成要素
that it is predicted
それが予測されているということ
That is to say, it is possible to do this
つまり、こんなこともできるのです
But I haven't at least in science
でも、少なくとも科学はやったことがない
That is to say, I don't know which newspaper to read.
つまり、どの新聞を読めばいいのか分かりません。
at least in this
少なくともこの中では
I don't know if the internet has seen it
ネット上で見られたかどうかは分かりませんが、
That is to say, this aspect of the article
つまり、この記事のこの部分は、
then we can go back
そうすれば戻れるよ
look at this aspect
この側面を見てください
I can only tell you today that I don't know
今日は知らないとしか言​​えない
probably still some distance
おそらくまだ距離がある
still some distance
まだ少し距離がある
are there any other questions
他に質問はありますか
there is one over there
あそこに1つあります
Hello, teacher. I am the student of this year's position.
こんにちは、先生、私は今年の生徒です。
then i want to ask
それから聞きたいです
Is that I'm subservient to the front until now down
今まで前に従順だったのか
Actually I have been having a problem
実は悩みを抱えていたんです
That is to say, when we are doing genetic modification
つまり、遺伝子組み換えを行う場合、
That's when we were doing Trims Form
それは私たちがTrims Formをやっていたときです
why can't we say
なぜ言えないのか
It's the one that let the farmer plant it
農家に植えさせたものです
genetically modified plants
遺伝子組み換え植物
the first offspring
最初の子孫
There is no way to continue to produce a second offspring
2人目の子孫を作り続ける方法はありません
Is there any other issue involved?
他に何か問題が関係していますか?
because i knew it was
そうだとわかっていたから
We have this technology in
私たちはこの技術を持っています
But it seems there is no way to do it
しかしそれを行う方法はないようです
You say you want them to have only the first offspring
あなたは彼らに最初の子孫だけを残したいと言いました
But I can't go down and plant myself
しかし、私は降りて自分自身を植えることはできません
Yes because it is to avoid
そう、避けるためだから
because when we choose
なぜなら私たちが選択するとき
we are usually in
私たちは通常中にいます
and some other antibiotic genes
および他のいくつかの抗生物質遺伝子
If we want to avoid the spread of its genes
その遺伝子の拡散を避けたい場合
Does that mean that it cannot produce a second generation?
ということは、第二世代は作れないということでしょうか？
This approach should be better
このアプローチの方が良いはずです
I think it should be theoretically possible to do so
理論的にはそれが可能なはずだと思う
But that means you can put
しかし、それはあなたが置くことができることを意味します
You can have this mechanism of marriage paper
結婚届のこの仕組みができます
you can even put
置くこともできます
I think in theory you could
理論的にはできると思います
That is to say, the gene jumped out in the second generation
つまり第二世代で遺伝子が飛び出した
should be no problem
問題ないはずです
should theoretically be able to do
理論的にはできるはずです
It's just that I think most of it, at least I think it means
それは私がそれのほとんどを考えているというだけです、少なくとも私はそれが意味するものだと思います
The way I tell you is
私があなたに伝える方法は、
That Meng Shantou they are controlling
彼らが支配している孟汕頭
because they sold that seed
彼らはその種を売ったので
They don't want the farmers to harvest the seeds themselves and plant them again
彼らは農家が自分たちで種子を収穫し、再び植えることを望んでいません。
Don't buy seeds from him
彼から種を買わないでください
So they're a farmer with you
つまり、彼らもあなたと同じ農家なのです
How many seeds do you plant a year and he takes pictures of you
あなたが一年に何本の種を植えると、彼はあなたの写真を撮ります
If you didn’t buy many seeds from him in the second year, he will sue you
2年目に彼から種子をあまり買わなかったら、彼はあなたを訴えるでしょう
if you plant it
それを植えたら
You planted more seeds than you bought from him
あなたは彼から買った種よりも多くの種を植えました
he will sue you
彼はあなたを訴えるでしょう
How many other farmers have been paid millions of dollars
他に何百万ドルも支払われた農家が何人いるか
I just turned him upside down
私は彼をひっくり返しただけです
i think you planted
あなたが植えたと思います
If you want to give to the peasants, you should give to the peasants
農民に与えたいなら農民に与えるべきだ
As long as it is your own designed savings
自分で計画した貯蓄である限り
Without the possibility of environmental pollution
環境汚染の可能性がないこと
because your first generation
なぜならあなたの第一世代だから
if you are afraid
恐れているなら
I am afraid that the second generation and the first generation should not go out.
二代目と初代は出てはいけないのではないかと思います。
I think the businessman gave us three heads, of course he would like to have this
ビジネスマンは私たちに頭を 3 つくれたと思います、もちろんこれが欲しいと思っています
put me right upside down
私を逆さまにしてください
This second generation like the recent
この二代目も最近のような
glowfish they quadruple him
彼らは彼を4倍にするグローフィッシュ
he won't pass it down
彼はそれを引き継がないだろう
Otherwise, if your fish is sold, they will keep raising it
そうでなければ、魚を売れば、彼らは魚を育て続けるでしょう。
don't do your business
自分の用事をしないでください
Yes, different considerations
はい、さまざまな考慮事項があります
But farmers are stronger, so it should be
でも農民の方が強いんだからそうなるはずだ
ok so last two questions
さて、最後の 2 つの質問
Excuse me, sir, I have a very simple question for you
すみません、とても簡単な質問があります。
That's our one, we're only talking about rice now
それは私たちのものです、今はご飯のことだけを話しています
Is there a way to turn vegetables from aerobic respiration
野菜の好気呼吸を防ぐ方法はあるのでしょうか？
Switch to anaerobic respiration, so you won't be afraid of typhoons
無酸素呼吸に切り替えれば台風も怖くない
it's all rotten thanks
全部腐ってるよ、ありがとう
I mean, switch to aerobic, switch to anaerobic
つまり、有酸素運動に切り替え、無酸素運動に切り替えます
All plants will have proof for you
すべての植物はあなたのために証拠を持っています
So it should be some other mechanism
したがって、それは別のメカニズムであるはずです
It can't be filled for a long time
長い間埋まらない
the vegetables our next step is
野菜、次のステップは
we make rice from that
それからお米を作ります
And do the so-called Arab world, learned
そして、いわゆるアラブ世界をやってください、学んだ
we are going to start now
今から始めます
talks about cutting plants
植物の伐採についての話
We Taiwanese farmers are actually very smart
私たち台湾の農民は実はとても賢いのです
we haven't invented yet
私たちはまだ発明していない
They have come up with some solutions
彼らはいくつかの解決策を考え出しました
they put that
彼らはそれを置きました
It's just that it's not easy to change money.
ただ、お金を両替するのは簡単ではありません。
Some are actually very antigenic
実際に非常に抗原性の高いものもあります
They use cheap
彼らは安いものを使っています
so you don't have to do anything
だから何もする必要はない
It's good to change chicken to beans
チキンをビーンズに変えても良いですね
And our farmers in Taiwan are very powerful
台湾の農家は非常に強力です
They can even mechanize the price street
彼らは価格設定を機械化することさえできる
So how many hundreds of dollars do you want to buy from him?
それで、あなたは彼から何百ドル買いたいですか？
I'll give it to you in a week
一週間以内にお渡しします
So I buy from them for experiments
だから私は実験のために彼らから購入します
I don't have to go by myself
自分で行く必要はない
So some farmers are better than me
だから私より優れた農家もいる
so vegetables are
だから野菜は
vegetables are better
野菜の方が良い
Because vegetables usually if they are leafy vegetables
野菜は葉物野菜であれば大抵あるので
you want leaves
葉っぱが欲しいの
So use the price street method
したがって、プライスストリートメソッドを使用します
Our Taiwanese bitter gourd and loofah
台湾ゴーヤとヘチマ
This is all solved by this
これで全て解決です
But when the typhoon came, the leafy vegetables were all destroyed.
ところが、台風が来て、葉物野菜が全部ダメになってしまいました。
right so
そうそう
The problem is that in fact
問題は、実際には
If you let it become antigenic water
抗原水にすると
probably means
おそらく意味します
often some are
多くの場合、いくつかは
make it look bad
見た目を悪くする
That is to say, what you gain is what you lose
つまり、得たものは失うものである
import a feature
フィーチャをインポートする
it tends to
そうなる傾向があります
But what we're thinking now is that this mechanism is
しかし、私たちが今考えているのは、このメカニズムは
It only activates when you're flooded
浸水した場合のみ発動する
It's not like water until those mechanisms are always there
それらのメカニズムが常に存在するまでは水とは言えません
so we are thinking
それで私たちは考えています
Vegetables may be simpler than water
野菜は水よりも単純かもしれない
Because usually we resolve by saying
なぜなら、通常私たちはこう言うことで解決するからです。
You change to anaerobic and non-inhalation method
無酸素・非吸入法に変更します
A gene is expressed more
遺伝子がより多く発現する
it's more stuck
それはもっと行き詰まっています
so this is ok
それで大丈夫です
so only when i come back
だから戻ってきたときだけ
never thought of doing this
これをすることを考えたこともなかった
Running every time a typhoon comes
台風が来るたびに走る
I'm thinking about it now
今それについて考えています
So we'll start doing that
それではこれを始めましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
and the last one
そして最後のもの
Supost let me ask a question
サポストに質問させてください
Questions that might stray from your topic today
今日のテーマから外れる可能性のある質問
It is about the market supply and demand of food
それは市場の食料の供給と需要に関するものです
I am a Meng Yichang
私は孟宜昌です
Now seven or eight years ago in Taiwan we had that except bemi
さて、7、8年前、台湾ではベミを除いてそれがありました
That surplus of old rice is almost going to the shop
その余った古米はもうすぐ店に行きます
Encourage soldiers and college students to eat more rice
兵士や大学生にもっと米を食べるよう奨励する
at that time
その時
The welfare soldiers are short of about 2.8 million tons of 10 meters
福祉兵士には10メートルの重さが約280万トン不足している
It was time for the overworked President of Asda
過労のアスダ社長の時間だ
I used to do business at that time
当時私は営業をしていました
At that time, I loved Taiwan and wanted to sell this rice there.
当時、私は台湾が大好きで、このお米を台湾で売りたいと考えていました。
Turns out Taiwan is very bureaucratic
台湾は非常に官僚的であることが判明
All of a sudden, the Central Trust Bureau by bidding
突然、中央信託局による入札
It's only 10,000 to 20,000 tons at a time
一度に10,000～20,000トンしかない
And I have to Zengxun, pack and transport
そして私はZengxun、梱包して輸送しなければなりません
wow that's tiring so i'm from vietnam
うわー、疲れたのでベトナムから来ました
They're all packed and shipped to the next one for sale there.
それらはすべて梱包されて、次の販売店に出荷されます。
So just now you mentioned again
それで、今またおっしゃいましたね
Welfare soldiers can do three goods in a row, right?
福祉兵はグッズを3回連続でできるんですよね？
There should be no shortage of rice
米が不足するはずがない
Why is he still missing more than two million tons in a row?
なぜまだ200万トン以上も連続して不足しているのでしょうか？
that currently
それは現在
I don't know if there is any improvement, I don't know
改善があるかどうかはわかりません、わかりません
These people, my master, can come to ask you for advice
この人たちは、私のマスター、あなたにアドバイスを求めに来ることができます
Why
なぜ
Let's just say go to the International Waterways Center every year
毎年国際水路センターに行くとしましょう。
At dusk, the International Waterway Center is at Huilibin
夕暮れ時、恵里浜の国際水路センター
so they feel ashamed
だから彼らは恥ずかしいと思う
The world's best waterway research center
世界最高の水路研究センター
Every year in Huilibin
恵里浜では毎年
In fact, when it is politically stable
実際、政治的に安定しているときは、
not like this
こんなんじゃない
Huilibin is actually very rich in nature.
恵里浜は実は自然がとても豊かです。
He has no reason not to be autonomous
彼には自主性を持たない理由がない
so it's a matter of politics
だからそれは政治の問題だ
rather than an economic or agricultural issue
経済や農業の問題ではなく
because of their social policy
彼らの社会政策のせいで
Nearby their rich and poor
近くにいる金持ちも貧乏人も
right
右
If you want the government to have a heart
政府に心を持ってもらいたいなら
Like Vietnam becoming the second largest in the world within a few years
ベトナムが数年以内に世界第二位になるみたいに
the rice exporting country
米の輸出国
You can see they use
彼らが使用しているのがわかります
the technology they use
彼らが使用しているテクノロジー
I'm with that silent teacher
あの無口な先生と一緒だよ
COA wants us to evaluate them
COA は私たちにそれらを評価してほしいと考えています
because of them
彼らのせいで
because
なぜなら
WTO relationship we have to import 6% of rice every year
WTOの関係で毎年米の6％を輸入しなければならない
so we buy it ourselves
だから自分たちで買うんだ
Taiwan has always sold in the United States
台湾は常に米国で販売してきました
Recently, Vietnam has been selling
最近ベトナムでも売れています
then we are
それなら私たちは
The rice imported from the United States we are
私たちが扱うお米はアメリカから輸入しています。
Sampling
サンプリング
Vietnamese rice we are
私たちはベトナム米です
Check each batch
バッチごとに確認してください
The Council of Agriculture wants us to go
農業評議会は私たちに行くことを望んでいます
look at him
彼を見て
the one you produced
あなたがプロデュースしたもの
When we came back from that process, we suggested to him that we should come back.
そのプロセスから戻ってきたとき、私たちは彼に「戻ってこよう」と提案しました。
Continue to check without package
パッケージなしでチェックを続ける
That
それか
So but as long as the country has that, they are very labor-intensive
しかし、国がそれを持っている限り、彼らは非常に労働集約的です
So their current rice
それで彼らの現在のお米は
Even though the quality is not good
たとえ品質が良くなくても、
but they have enough
しかし、彼らは十分に持っています
There's no reason not to do well
うまくいかない理由はない
That's his social structure and his political problems
それが彼の社会構造と政治的問題だ
this
これ
no one can help
誰も助けられない
only themselves
自分たちだけ
they have the best
彼らは最高のものを持っています
world
世界
best waterway
最高の水路
The research center is just at Rose Beach, just at the establishment of diplomatic relations in Marilla, he has no reason to do it
研究センターはローズビーチにあり、マリラとの国交樹立の時期に、彼にはそうする理由がない
Moreover, there are thousands of islands, and the lack of thousands of islands is really
さらに、何千もの島がありますが、何千もの島が欠けているのは本当に問題です。
More than two million tons a year
年間200万トン以上
Every time you go to our Guojin rice center, you are really bad
私たちの国金ライスセンターに行くたびに、あなたは本当に悪いです
no split price
分割価格なし
Well, thanks, we actually I have two observations that I have today
そうですね、ありがとう、実は今日は 2 つの観察があります。
see so many people come to listen
たくさんの人が聞きに来ているのを見てください
It can be seen that everyone is interested in these agricultural
誰もがこれらの農業に興味を持っていることがわかります
The topic is also very concerned, I think it's pretty good
話題もとても気になるところです、なかなか良いと思います
Without agriculture, we would have no food, this is very serious
これは農業がなければ食べるものがなくなる、これは非常に深刻です
So this another
それで、これはもう一つ
What the mayor didn't talk about, what he just said
市長が語らなかったこと、今言ったこと
farmers these our technology is very good and so on
農家の皆さん、私たちの技術はとても優れています。
but
しかし
how do we do this
これをどうやって行うか
Actually just with this
実はこれだけで
The fact that the second generation is not long has a little bit to do with how we protect our own sanctions
第二世代が長くないという事実は、私たちが自らの制裁をどのように守るかに少し関係しています。
It's a good thing developed.
開発されたのは良いことだ。
Unfortunately, many kinds of sneaks are now
残念ながら、現在では多くの種類のスニークが販売されています。
then run across from us
それから私たちの向かいに走って行きます
Then grow something and sell it to us
それから何かを育てて私たちに販売してください
this is also a problem
これも問題です
So in this new species you make
それで、あなたが作るこの新しい種では
or these things
またはこれらのこと
how do we protect ourselves
どうやって自分たちを守るのか
If you can have this idea
このアイデアを持っていただければ
Then he will use this thing
そうしたら彼はこれを使うでしょう
we can take his money
私たちは彼のお金を受け取ることができます
so we can make more money to
それで私たちはもっとお金を稼ぐことができます
Otherwise, Taiwan will have problems in the future
そうしないと将来台湾に問題が起きるだろう
we are so small
私たちはとても小さいです
no way to compete
競争する方法がない
well, thank you very much for coming
さて、来てくれてありがとう
thank you
ありがとう